Heat. Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Welcome Living Mana Church family. It's
so good to see you here today on the
Sabbath. It's every Sabbath is a
blessing, but today this Sabbath is a
blessing. As you can see, we are on the
road living mana uh on the road Sabbath.
So, we're in one of our remote studios,
but we are happy to be able to be here.
And we are here because we have a new
grandson. That's right.
>> Our grandson was born this week.
Luca Royce Allen.
>> Royce Allen.
>> And if you're wondering where the names
came from, I mean Luca, his parents came
up with Luca, but they also gave them
pastor's middle name. Gave them gave him
[laughter] pastor's middle name, Royce.
Um, and so we are very happy, not just
because of the middle name, but because
he's here and he's healthy and doing so
well, and we are thankful and praise
God. So thank you for all your well
wishes for those who said you were
praying and that we're praying uh for
everything for the whole pregnancy of
our daughter. Everything was really
really good. So we are very very
thankful. So yes. So with that please
put in the chat where you are viewing
from. We want to if this is your first
time put a one give us your name where
you're viewing from. We want to say a
special welcome to you. If you are our
regulars, please, we love to see you
here and we want to say uh a special
welcome to you. So, please uh start
putting in the chat where you're viewing
from. I see a lot of you are saying
congratulations. Thank you so much.
>> We are thrilled. We are very thrilled um
to just have our um our second grandson.
Our second We have three grandchildren
now. Okay, I'm probably talking a lot
about this, but we have
>> second grandson. second grandson.
>> It's uh
>> Yes,
>> it's a beautiful experience.
>> Definitely a beautiful experience.
>> Absolutely.
>> All right, [clears throat] so we have
Veronica from Washington State. Welcome.
Good to see you here. Welcome to Living
Man Church. Uh we have Oklahoma City
here. Welcome. Happy Sabbath to you. We
are just thrilled to have you. All
right, we have Minnesota. I don't know
the name. I can't see the name, but uh
welcome.
It's good to see all of you. We got
Atlanta. Welcome to different
I should say. So, we're excited uh to
have you here with
Island of Bermuda. Haven't been there
for a while.
>> Go see
turquoise uh waters right uh by the
ocean. Right by the airport, I should
say. Right by the ocean. right by the
airport. It's like it's the first thing
you see. I'm like, "Oh, it's so
beautiful." So, welcome. Um, from
Bermuda, also we have South Carolina.
Welcome, John and Ashley. Great to see
you and have you here with us. We have
Sacramento, Sack Town. Welcome. Good to
good to see you here. Um, also Brooklyn,
New York. We have Did I miss I think we
got Tennessee, Murphy'sboro, of course,
Nicole. Always good to see our sweet
Nicole um here at Living Mana Church.
Such a blessing to the church. Thank
you, Nicole, for all that you do.
Talented, just beautiful.
>> Amen.
>> Young lady. So, yes, welcome. I can go
on. But again, if you are here for the
first time, please put a one in the chat
so uh we could just tell you a little
bit more about our church and everyone
can welcome you, not just us, but those
in the chat can welcome you as well. I
just see here we have Brazil. Welcome,
Juliana from Brazil.
Good to see you here again. Um Juliana,
always good to see you. Uh Jennifer's
from Tennessee. Welcome. Good to see you
here. Um as well. Yes. So, we could just
go on and on and on, but we do have a
Sabbath school.
>> All right. And just want you guys to
know, not quite ready for the t-shirt
message, but about to do a turn, but um
just want you guys [clears throat] to
know that we are we will be having a
baptism, which um we are shooting for
sometime in February. And this is this
is the baptism that we were not able to
do in November because of the government
shutdown. Um but we are going to that
baptism is going to happen. Um and there
will maybe be even new people that will
be a part of it as well. So, please look
forward uh to that.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
>> T-shirt
>> t-shirt message.
>> Only Jesus can turn a mess to a message,
a test into a testimony, a trial into a
triumph, and a victim into a victory.
>> Amen. So, um I mean the shirt is very
self-explanatory, but sometimes we
forget all of this when we're going
through something. All we do, all we can
do is just focus on the negative thing
that's going on or the current
situation. And we feel like, remember,
we I'm saying feel like we can't think
like this.
>> But we can think like this when you're
in the middle of a trial, when you're in
the middle of a situation that's not
going your way. The enemy tries to come
to us like, "Nope, you have to think how
you feel." But you don't. You can. We
God is so good. He made our brains
powerful enough to actually be able to
pivot and switch the way we're uh
thinking because of the way that we're
feeling, but to actually make a
[clears throat] choice to say, "Okay,
I'm feeling this way, but I'm choosing
to believe, have faith, and think this
way about the situation. I don't see the
victory. I don't see the triumph. I
don't see the change situation, but God
has given us the power to switch our
mindset and think differently about
what's currently going on. Um, yeah. It
just makes me always think of my prayer
mentor, Janet Paige, which was always
like, she's like, "Okay, you're I'd call
her and tell her what I'm going
through." She's like, "Okay, okay, let's
just let's let's praise God right now."
>> What? I've mentioned that here before,
but it was like at first it was like,
"No, it's it's hard to do that, but we
can do it. We can praise God in the
middle of the situation."
>> Yeah.
>> So, this doesn't We feel this. We feel
no triumph, no victory, all of these
things, but we can have faith and
believe and change our thoughts. And
when we change our thoughts, it changes
our emotions. So even though we're going
through something, have you ever seen
somebody going through something, but
they're peaceful?
>> Because they've changed their thoughts
about what's going on.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> that can be for all of us.
>> Does that go with your sermon?
>> It does.
>> And I don't even know what you're
saying.
>> And you've actually you've actually
added some without even knowing it,
you've added some
>> Good. will give me some credit in the
middle of [laughter]
I'm kidding. [gasps]
But yeah, that's the
>> But uh you will hear it in the sermon.
>> Amen. Well, amening when I hear it.
>> And by the way, guys, today, you know,
typically wait till at the uh end of
Sabbath school to do this, but you know,
today's sermon uh is entitled the hidden
kingdom. and um really some powerful
revelations, some things that I have not
put together before
>> um that just kind of changes
the way that we
uh see
>> and understand the kingdom of heaven.
>> Amen.
>> So, uh look for look forward to it.
>> Yes. Look forward
>> going to be a good manner today.
>> Yes. Look forward to [clears throat] it.
Please like and subscribe um on the
YouTube channel that you are watching
right now and share. So you go you like
you share and subscribe. Three things
three things if you have not already
done that.
>> But definitely all of you should be
sharing because this is this is today's
message. So all of you should be
sharing. Invite somebody to church uh to
be able to worship with us. We'd love to
for you to to to to uh be a part of that
and work with us and getting more people
coming to have to be able to feed on the
living mana that is provided here at
Living Mana Church. So, please do that.
Um and we just want to get started in
Sabbath school. All right.
And yes, so I saw there were some more.
I missed some. I think I saw Vancouver,
Canada. Was it? Oh, no. I had a
Vancouver candidate or I think it was
one of the the island. So, welcome. I
know I missed I saw it but I missed you.
So,
it's good to have you here with us and
all right, I think we're ready to pray
and introduce our topic for today.
[clears throat]
>> Yep. And John, I just uh put a message
to you in the chat. So, let let's we're
going to connect again. Okay.
>> All right. Um, so
let's uh we should let you know let our
members know, let our people know that
uh this Sabbath school is actually
>> um like a last minute thing.
>> Like when we say last minute like super
like right before we went to bed last
minute last minute last night.
>> Last minute. Yeah. That's because you
know, you know, well,
>> we like to say stay current with the
news. You know, when I say stay current,
when it when it applies to things
biblically or in the Bible or what it is
impacting our, you know, Christians or
that type of thing. So, or just people
in general, we want to uh we used to
host a program, this is years ago, this
is
>> over 20 years ago, but we used to do a
radio program called World News and the
Bible
>> with Pastor Steve Wahberg. So, um,
anyways, this is world news and the
Bible today for Sabbath school because
it's going on currently.
>> That's right.
>> Yes.
>> With some, uh, pretty significant
update, uh, um, events or an event that
has occurred.
>> Yes.
>> We shouldn't even say an event, but just
something that's unfolded that is very
significant to us as Seventh Day
Adventist. So,
>> right. And not Okay. Yeah. Let's pray.
>> Let's pray. Let's pray.
Heavenly Father, we thank you Lord um
for um this Sabbath Lord. We thank you
for this service. Uh we thank you for
the opportunity Lord to worship you
again and today Lord as we um begin this
discussion on this subject Lord please
speak uh through us Lord and uh again
Lord we pray that the trumpet will be
given a certain sound today um that we
will be awake and alert to what is going
on around us. We pray this in Jesus
name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
So,
okay, I'll start. I mean, you're gonna
definitely pick up, but I'll start. So,
I don't know if you guys saw, but um I
was going through Facebook and and I had
gone through earlier, but I didn't click
on it earlier, but last night I finally
did click on it, and it was a report
from the Associated Press. ABC was was
reporting on what the Associated Press
had put out. But
>> shall we read it?
>> Yes. But I just want to say Yeah. Yeah.
You're gonna read it. Um but the
Heritage Foundation is wanting this
administration
to um
>> Let's let let's let ABC say it.
>> Okay, I'll let ABC say it. Yeah.
>> All right. ABC. So, um, [clears throat]
because we're on the road, we can't
really share our screen, but I'm going
to read to you, uh, from, um, ABC News,
and we'll probably put the link. In
fact, I'm going to I'm just going to
copy this link and put it in the chat
right now for you guys.
Um,
okay. So there is the link and let me go
ahead and read
uh Heritage Foundation calls upon us to
prioritize prioritize marriage and
family in new report. Um the Heritage
Foundation think tank is urging the
federal government to save and restore
the American family
kicking off the midterm election year
with a call for conservatives to focus
on domestic issues. That's the heading.
And then here's what it goes on to say.
Uh, the Heritage Foundation think tank
is urging the federal government to save
and restore the American family, kicking
off the midterms. We just read that
among its recommendations,
a marriage boot camp designed to prepare
cohabitating couples for marriage.
A, and I'm quoting now, I mean, I've
been quoting the whole thing, but a
quote, they have in quotation marks,
universal day of rest
that would build upon blue laws that
limit alcohol sales in some
municipalities and discouragement of
online dating,
in part because of research showing that
couples who meet online are also less
likely to get married in the first
place. The full plan, published Thursday
and first reported by the Washington
Post, marks the foundation's evolution
from its small government roots to a
pillar of the populist right. During
President Donald Trump's second term,
Heritage has demonstrated its impact
with Project 2025, which has been used
as a blueprint to overhaul US policy.
All right.
This is ABC
News
>> and they put in quotation marks
a universal
day of rest
>> right
>> and Karen Yep.
>> while it's happening
>> now. Um
what I what I don't want to do well let
me not say what I don't want to do. I
think what's important for us to
understand [clears throat and cough]
>> is once again how Bible prophecy
unfolds.
>> Is the sky falling?
>> No.
>> The sky is not falling. And yes, while
we're seeing this actually being
publicly
>> um uh pushed,
there are other events
that are important to understanding
prophec that are important in prophecy
that preede what is going to happen. But
I think this is important for this
reason
>> that it is showing us where this train
is headed.
Right.
>> Yes.
>> And let me say this,
>> it's
I think it we're in a scary place.
>> Yeah.
>> When this event is a wakeup call,
especially to Seventh Day Adventists,
>> right?
>> This should not be a wakeup call.
>> It shouldn't, but it's a blessing. It
shouldn't.
>> But it's God's grace and mercy
>> for so many who are just like, oh yeah,
where prophecy is just white noise.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's just like, h not focused on
that.
>> And God is allowing something so clear.
Not that this is definitely not the last
movements. There's
>> a lot that still needs to happen.
>> Yeah.
>> But it is a wakeup call and a great
opportunity
to share the truth. and it's connected
to project 2025. But
>> yeah,
so and I think one of the things I'm I
was pointing out as well is that,
you know, we've had people um saying,
"Hey, we don't know where the Sunday law
is going to come from, right? We don't
know how it's going to get pushed. It
could come from the secularists,
>> right?
>> It could come from the communists. Mhm.
>> It could come from the, you know,
>> the anti-religious
>> people, which again literally makes no
sense because
>> anti-religious people
>> are not going to push for a religious
observance,
>> right?
>> That is dedicated to that is supposedly
dedicated to honoring Jesus.
>> There's no atheist, no secularist, no
day of worship.
>> Yes. That's not like a national day of
worship.
>> Absolutely. That's just
>> it. It's that's that's pure
>> foolishness.
>> Foolishness. Um even the United Nations,
>> you know, there's a lot of talk lately,
you know, particularly within Adventist
circles of the United Nations. Thei
>> you guys, we what we need to understand
is that the United Nations is a secular
organization,
>> right?
um they are not going to be pushing
>> for a religious observance
>> of a day that is supposed to be
dedicated to honoring Jesus.
>> No. Right.
>> And so how we've gotten to the place
where we've become so mixed up and the
way that I I um the way that I think
it's important the way that I put this
is this.
A lot of us have become so caught up in
defending
um a particular version of Christianity,
>> right?
>> Particularly American Protestant
Christianity
>> that we're doing our best to try to
shield
>> everything that's happening in the
religious world within America.
>> You know, where we're so when people
talk about these things, we're we're
called political. Oh, you're being
political because you're saying that
>> uh you know the the political right is
is combining Christianity is using
Christianity
>> as a train right as a as a entering
wedge
>> to gain political power
>> and the fact that it is um it is
happening with a particular political
party
>> it's Almost as if the devil has
cunningly made it so that to talk about
it makes it appear that you're you're
being political.
>> Right.
>> You're just being political. And again,
I I cannot tell you how many people
have,
>> you know, oh yeah, Pastor Myers, yeah,
he got political.
>> And it really it's because of
>> I love to tell the Bible. Tell the
Bible. Tell the people that the Bible is
political then prophecy is political
because that's right.
>> That's it.
>> That's right. So, in other words, to not
talk about this, to in order to seem
like, oh, you're not being political,
the devil has brought it to a place
where if you talk about the Heritage
Foundation, if you talk about um uh
Turning Point USA, if you talk about
these organizations
that are at the forefront of pushing
Christianity
and and yet
>> doing so within the context of politics,
the very thing we have been warned
against,
>> the devil has made it so if you talk
about these things, particularly within
Adventist circles, you're being
political.
>> Right.
>> Right. You are being uh biased
>> because you're not talking about the the
quote unquote godless left. You're not
talking about the communists. You're not
talking about the atheists. But again
and again and I have said this time and
time again.
>> Mhm.
>> There are 42
chapters in the great controversy.
>> Right?
>> There are 22 chapters in the book of
revelation.
>> There are 12 chapters in the book of
Daniel. Of those chapters in the book of
Revelation, one chapter is dedicated
towards atheism. That's Revelation
chapter 11. Every other chapter,
>> yes,
>> is pointing to the dangers of the and
the what leads up to and the end result
of mingling Christianity with politics.
In the book of Daniel,
a portion of Daniel chapter 11
>> is dedicated to anti-God powers to to to
openly uh anti-Christian powers. the
king of the south.
>> Every other chapter in Daniel
>> is a prophetic
uh layout
of [clears throat]
the danger of mixing religion with
politics.
>> In the great controversy, there is one
chapter, literally one chapter, the
chapter on the French Revolution that is
dedicated towards the results of
rejecting Christianity.
every other chapter in that book
>> is showing the the the path the trail
>> uh that leads to and the end result of
mixing Christianity with politics
>> and by and large what we are seeing from
[snorts]
the right and now I don't care if you're
like oh he's being political
>> right I'm just because there's oh cut
you off [laughter] go ahead finish It
what we are seeing
on the political right is what we have
been warned about in Bible prophecy
>> for years [snorts]
>> for years.
Yes. Yeah. Listen,
>> I like the way John Hensley
Heasley says it. The Heritage Foundation
is since I started reading it, I lost
it. But the Heritage Foundation is
>> couching
>> in family uh
>> Sunday in this family and wellness.
Absolutely. Family. Yes. Because because
it doesn't just come and say, "Let's,
>> you know, they don't want to um try to
really push the administration to to
have a national day of worship, but also
for um in that same article, they're
talking about um telling people to have
children.
>> Yeah. quickly, not wait to do their
career,
>> but to get married and to have children
right away and to and to not not to push
it, you know, down the road. Um,
>> they have a lot of things in there that
are very strange, but it's couch, but it
looks like, oh, we're just trying to
>> just give time for family and to
reconnect and it just
>> Yeah.
>> And and I want you to just note like why
this push for family. You you even
heard, you know, in in Turning Point,
you turning point There was a huge thing
about have kids, have kids. It the goal
is not to populate the earth.
>> It's to have more conservative
>> absolutely
>> to mindset people to vote way. That's
just in their mind.
>> That's right. So conversion then is
based on two things.
>> The government becoming Christian
>> mercy
>> and
through uh childbearing. And I just want
to say for those of you who don't
follow, I just want to say this. Some of
you [clears throat] might be like, where
do they say that? They are what we just
said. They are very open.
>> Have more kids. Have more kids. Have
children. Yeah.
>> Yes. Because the two biggest I think not
really think tanks, but organizations
would be Heritage Foundation and Turning
Point USA.
>> And they are both huge. I would say
um the the the Heritage Foundation would
focus more on uh seasoned older people.
No, I say older. And then the turning
point is on the youth. So they're coming
from it from both sides.
>> Um and they're very they're very what we
just said they say all the time.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> yeah. and and and and so conversion
again
>> is um based on not based on the Holy
Spirit
>> but based on have more kids and let the
government dictate what Christianity
>> uh should be right let the government
let the government create laws that will
enforce
>> a Christian worldview
>> when you don't have the Holy Holy Spirit
working on your side.
>> Yeah,
>> that is what you you
>> revert to
>> super. Yes.
>> So it is interesting that what they are
actually seeking to do
>> is return to a Genesis 1 and two model
>> where you have the two institutions, the
twin institutions of marriage
>> and the Sabbath.
>> That's what they're doing.
>> Okay. marriage,
>> family,
>> and the Sabbath. God creates marriage.
Adam and Eve, Genesis 1, Genesis 2, you
have the Sabbath command. You have this,
you know, the the Sabbath being
instituted.
>> So, it's interesting
>> trying to recreate the garden. They're
trying to recreate
>> mercy
>> the the the original
>> plan of God
>> through use of government force. and
they're going back to the very beginning
where humanity went wrong and just like
okay we're gonna yeah
>> start right there
>> family and Sabbath. I want to again for
those who don't follow maybe things as
closely as we tend to do or others do
you think like okay that's Heritage
Foundation that's Turning Point USA okay
okay those are just two organizations no
they're not just two organizations they
um have the ear well you saw um at at
Charlie Kirk's u memorial service
[clears throat]
>> the entire cabinet
>> of this administration spoke.
These two organizations have the ear of
of the president and other powerful
people within the administration to just
walk into [clears throat] the White
House and say
>> this is what we are wanting to do.
Remember this is coming from um project
2025. So
>> So do you remember I'm cutting you off.
>> I know. I was going to say the whole
basis, the whole the whole way that
project 2025 works is by having the um
the ear and the power to to make the
government that's in or the
administration that's in office now to
do what they want to do. And so and
they've already started those things.
That's not new. In this past year,
>> many of their things that they were
wanting have been implemented.
>> Yep. Um,
again,
I think it is it's
it's a scary thing to see how many
Adventists
have gone along with so much of what has
been happening with this Christian
political push, right? The defending of
um of uh
of Christian nationalism.
um seeking to divert attention from oh
Sunday law it could you don't know where
it could come from you know why are you
speaking so confidently that it's going
to be coming from you know the the
political right well
>> forget about the political right
wherever you see politics and
Christianity being merged into a
political movement that's where we ought
to be looking and because so many of us
who who who claim to be oh we're not
political but yet are so politically
invested that you're doing everything
possible to defend your to defend
Christian nationalism and say, "Oh, it's
not really a thing."
>> The denial is kind of crazy,
>> right? Mhm.
>> Um
I wonder
it's it's kind of amazing how you know
15 20 years ago had this very article
come out
>> every Adventist pulpit every Adventist
media would be like boom. But
>> the devil has pulled off something
within the last 10 to 15 years that is
so
I hate to use any other word for it but
brilliant.
>> Yeah,
>> it's brilliant.
>> Mhm. that he has brought so many
Adventists into a state of silence
>> and denial over the things that are
happening and that have been happening
>> all under the guise
>> because they linked their their anchor
if you will
>> with
>> to this train.
>> Yes.
Because of
>> well they're the obvious listen they're
the obvious Christian people they stand
against abortion. they
>> they're against um same-sex marriage,
you know, those type of things. So,
okay. So, that too
>> I'm with
>> Yeah.
>> Where
>> and I think it has it has
>> abortion, samesex marriage, all of those
things are things that your relationship
with God
and not the government, but your
relationship with God should dictate how
you live and decisions you make in your
life, not the government.
>> Yeah. And so, it's funny. I I wasn't
even planning to bring this up, but um I
I will say this
[clears throat] and I don't even know
what I want to call it yet.
Um but you you will see and and if
you're listening, you're listening. Um
you who we talked yesterday, you will
see within the Christian world, right?
There's this big push of, you know, this
big debating point of what is a man?
>> What is a woman?
>> Can you define what a woman is?
>> And you know, the Christian world in
this in this Christian debate world,
it's like there's this kind of mocking
of you can't even tell what a woman is,
right? What is a woman? What is a man?
And you know, for the liberals, oh, you
can't define what a woman or a man is. M
>> um and that's in that whole trans world.
Right.
>> Right.
>> I think the same kind of confusion is in
the Christian world.
>> So I'm going to call it trans
Christianity
>> where
people are now confused about what a
Christian is.
>> What is a Christian? Mhm.
>> And the answer that is given is as crazy
and as off as what they say is happening
in the trans world of what is a man,
what is what is a woman because what is
passing now for Christianity
>> is totally
>> outside of what the Bible says.
>> Right. Right.
>> Right.
>> And so many people now are literally
confusing what a Christian actually is.
>> What's a Christian? I let I will say
this way, trans Christianity
>> where you can be a Christian and support
these things and hold these things to be
true and support these people that do
this, this, this, and this, and this,
and yet still say, "Yeah, I'm a
Christian." No, that's not a Christian.
>> It It's not
>> right. And what these movements are
doing is they're redefining what it
means to be a Christian. Mhm.
>> So, as long as you stand behind a a
particular political party
>> and as long as you have these political
positions, you are a Christian.
>> No, that's trans Christianity.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. That's not real Christianity.
>> You that is not real Christianity. Is
something that is that is biblical
and not political. Mhm.
>> So, I'm going to come back to that in a
moment, right?
>> I'm going to come back to that at
another time. Let me say, but here's
what we need to understand, you guys,
that
this call. Oh, by the way, let's go to
the heritage Heritage Foundation because
yeah,
>> when you sent me the article last night,
I was like, well, let me go see what
Heritage Foundation actually has to say,
>> right? We'll go deeper into that. And
please, this is Sabbath school, guys.
You can comment, put your questions
about this topic. This is what we're
talking about today.
>> So on the Heritage Foundation uh
website, this was just put out uh August
January.
>> And if they want to read it for
themselves, they're not seeing this. So
you just go to the Heritage Foundation,
I'm assuming.com. I don't see the
>> I'm going to go ahead and put this.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. I may I Yeah.
>> So yeah, I may have a sermon coming up
called TransChristian.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> TransChristianity.
>> Okay.
>> Um,
>> and so yes, please click on that link to
read along with pastor right now or read
it later. But that's
>> okay. Yeah.
>> So that's the link and I'm just going to
I'm going to go down to the the section
called support for a uniform day of
rest. Now ABC News said a universal day
of rest. They put it in quotation marks
a universal day of rest. But Heritage
Foundation didn't use the term
universal. Not that I saw. but a uniform
>> a uniform
>> day of rest. And I [clears throat] just
want to say again before you even read
this, remember project 2025
>> push for this
>> which was built out from the Heritage
Foundation. Um they tried to be like
okay well you know of course Sunday is
the rest but if
>> you have um
is it job issues or no if it was not
even that if if if you're you know it
could
>> it started off with a you know whatever
your day is
>> whatever your day is
>> but Sunday is really the main day.
>> Yes. Oh, absolutely. And then that also
I just want to say this too for those of
you might be saying because we talked
about Turning Point USA. So I mean
Charlie Kirk's book that came out also
says pick a day. So okay. All right. So
let's
>> and again I think what is what is so sad
about that whole thing is how many how
many of us just kind of jumped on this
bandwagon pushing this idea pushing this
oh oh go out and get this. go and get
this. Go buy the book.
>> Something I mean, I know you're about to
read it and we keep talking before you
read it, but something else because
we're talking about the book and why
those who were supporting it and when it
came out, they're like, "Oh, oops."
Meaning, yes, there are
>> I mean, knowledge of good and evil,
there's always a mix, right?
>> Um, but
um there's a big there's ch there's a
whole chapter on the blue laws,
>> which um Heritage Foundation mentions
that too. So they're wanting to turn
>> America back to a national day of
worship
>> according to the blue laws. They
specifically say that. So for those of
you who like where are the Adventist
church always talking about these
national Sunday blue laws, those are
real and they've been on the books for
years. So that's like not
>> So yeah. Yeah. So here's what's
happening. I think two things are
happening. Number one,
>> the critics who are like this will never
happen in America.
>> Yeah. and Adventists are off and
Adventists are wrong.
>> You you need to go back to them with
with with the Associated Press article.
>> Yeah. Like
I I wonder how much it will take for
those who are critical of the Adventist
understanding of prophecy
>> to see
>> guys look at what's going on,
>> right?
>> Look at the political religio political
movement that is a foot. Look at what
they're pushing.
>> What are the odds? What are the odds
that over a hundred plus years ago we
just made this up and here it is now
coming to pass. What are the odds of
that?
>> Okay.
>> No. No. Yeah.
>> Number one. Number two, what are the
odds or how sad is it that not only do
our critics reject this notion, but now
even many among us are found pushing and
supporting
>> the very movements
the very movements
>> all because well they agree
[clears throat] with us on abortion
>> or they agree with us on the on the
family
>> or they're trying to keep transgender
something something out of something. I
mean like
>> I mean talk about the tree of the
knowledge of good and evil.
>> Talk about eating from the tree of the
>> It it's it's just stunning.
>> It's just stunning. So
once again, yeah, many are so entrenched
that in this that they won't listen. And
again,
oh, you're being political if you talk
about this,
>> right?
>> And yet at the same time,
>> Mhm.
>> Uh, we're talking about the United
Nations. We're talking about climate
change.
>> We're talking about
>> mercy
>> the, you know,
uh, how climate change is going to bring
in Sunday. all these things you guys
while and I'm not saying everybody's
doing this
>> but what I'm saying is that how is it
that we
that we have so lost focus that
something like this could be happening
right now
>> and by and large
there's again not everybody's solid but
by and large there's pretty much just
like crickets like
>> yeah nothing's going on
>> okay So
>> yeah,
>> let's go back to Heritage Foundation.
>> So I just saw somebody
>> We're going to come to that. I'm going
to we're going to address why the sky is
not falling.
>> Right. Right.
>> And Yeah. So 1999.
>> That's who.
>> Okay. Yeah. Well, this happened this
year. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And we're going to get to that.
And I just want to push a pause. Um, as
I think the church's mental health,
[laughter]
not therapists [clears throat] or not
your guys' therapists, but mental
health, whatever you want to call me for
the church. Um, I don't want you to I
don't want you to have anxiety because
God doesn't give us the spirit of fear.
He is so good and merciful and and to us
that he definitely gives us uh he shows
us things. I mean, he he gave us
prophecies so that this wouldn't take us
by surprise. But because we haven't been
paying attention, I would say, you know,
so many have not been paying attention.
They may be taken by surprise. But he's
definitely God is not, you know, is not
leaving us or forsaking us. We can trust
in him, but we just need to refocus if
our focus was out of focus on what's
really happening. Yeah.
>> Um and again, and we're going to get to
that. I know that you're we're going to
get to that, but there's still things
that need to happen, but this is still
very significant. Very It's too
significant not to talk about it.
>> Yeah. So, let's let's go to Heritage
Foundation's
um [snorts] section here. The the art
the um document they just produ produced
and uh it says this under support for
uniform day of rest. As zoning laws
allows a community to determine where
one can operate certain businesses, blue
laws reflect the local judgment as to
when one can operate certain businesses.
In the case of McGawan versus Maryland
1961, the Supreme Court
held by an 8 to1 vote that Sunday
closing laws that include the purpose of
providing a uniform day of rest are
constitutional
and can accommodate the fact that the
majority of people who take a day off of
for of a day of rest for religious
reasons do so on Sundays.
Massachusetts, for example, requires
that every employer of of labor engaged
in carrying on manufacturing, mechanical
or merchantile establishment of work or
workshop shall allow every person at
least 24 consecutive hours of rest in
seven consecutive days. Day of rest laws
limiting commercial activity are usually
found in less dense populated countries
or counties, although restrictions on
alcohol sales are more widespread.
Though greatly diminished, blue laws
persist in some form in close to 28
states. These places serve as a sort of
legal reservoir. Once their day of rest
laws are abolished, they are very hard
to restore.
A uniform day of rest that limits
commercial activity can provide temporal
boundaries [clears throat]
that help communities to set aside time
for religious observance, family
gatherings, outdoor activities, and
rest. A stable base of research shows
that these practices correlate with
better mental health, stronger social
bonds, and more stable family
structures.
Um, and I'm just going to a couple more
paragraphs,
but I I'll read this. With the advent of
ondemand delivery, shopping can be
shifted easily and conveniently to other
days of the week by restoring a common
rhythm of rest and reflection. A common
rhythm of rest and reflection. Community
rest laws could help to reverse the
trend towards spiritual homelessness and
foster the social habits necessary for
communities to cohhere and flourish.
Okay.
So, and then they mentioned Chick-fil-A.
The popular ever popular Chick-fil-A
chain closes its restaurants on Sundays
for the benefit of its workers and their
families. where new planned communities
or transition communities form, they
should consider adding rest days as part
of their master plan for balancing and
thriving community life.
>> And yes, Chick-fil-A ownership is very
connected to um
>> I don't have all the facts, but I've
heard that they're very connected to I
don't know about this organization, but
that um same mindset. Oh, obviously
that's why they close that's why they
close on Sunday.
>> Yep.
>> Um
>> Yeah. Wow, that was a lot. Just reading
it from them, I'm thinking,
>> you want to make that, which sounds
good, a national thing in America.
America's filled with so many different
people from different religious beliefs
that don't believe in the Bible that,
you know, that
>> I like to say this, our best friends in
Alabama are our neighbors.
>> And they are Muslim.
>> And do you, you know what I'm saying?
like to be able to put that onto
everybody that has their own belief
system. That's not America.
>> That's right.
>> That's not America. That was that's not
what America was founded on. And that's
not the biblical foundation most
importantly.
>> Yeah.
So
>> I think
that what we have happening here now is
>> to address the question will this happen
this year,
>> right?
>> We don't know.
>> Well, there's a lot this needs to
happen. A lot would have to happen if
this is but I mean I mean yeah Ellen
White says the the final movements will
be
>> fast ones but there's a lot that would
need to happen this year. Mhm. So, think
of it like this, right?
We have we have taught
right time and time again that
no matter how hard of a push for Sunday
law
>> made by any organization, it's not going
to happen.
>> And the reason it's not going to happen
is because
there will be too much protest in the
streets.
>> That's right. Right? You're trying to
make I mean, think about it. America is
founded on religious liberty.
>> To go against the very thing that we
were founded on,
>> right?
>> It it would be World War
Five.
It would be chaos,
>> right?
>> And Bible prophecy does not speak to
chaos around the Sunday law. Mhm.
>> Bible prophecy says the entire world
>> there's unity
>> is united on this,
>> right? Which means if the entire world
is united on a Sunday law
>> whose main objective according to the
Bible
>> is not a secular day of rest but a
religious day of rest,
>> a Christian
religious day of rest. Then that
necessitates
>> that the entire world will be Christian
but trans Christian.
>> You're okay. trans Christian,
>> trans Christian,
>> and
>> not real Christian,
>> not genuine Christianity,
>> but a counterfeit version of
Christianity.
>> And
>> the government cannot
bring that to pass.
>> It must be something supernatural.
>> And that goes back that goes back to our
back to basics series. Put a one in the
chat if you guys saw Back to the Basics
series. That's if you've been following
us before Living Mana Church. Well,
we've played Back to the Basics series
here for Zabas fulltime, but it was
originally recorded
six years ago. Almost.
>> Oh my goodness. Is that that long? Wow.
Almost six years ago. Right at the
beginning of is when [clears throat] we
did Back to the Basics. But if you saw
Back to the Basics, put a one. But I
think some of the Back to the Okay,
we're getting the ones. I think some of
the back to the basic um not some but
the back to the basic series that we did
um will help you to understand that
these aren't this right here is not the
final event yet. Um, that's why we're
saying things have to still happen. And
like you said, the unity, like though I
said our our best friends are our
neighbors in Alabama and they are
Muslim,
we completely believe they're beautiful,
kind people. That's why they're our best
friends. They're just the most loving,
kind kindest people.
>> Um, but
our belief systems are completely
different.
So, so there's so many um
>> what are there one billion Muslims in
the world and then one billion um
Catholics I don't know what I mean and
so their
>> their belief systems are so different
but for the Sunday law to happen
everyone is going to come together
>> that we are nowhere near that
>> but the whirlwind one will bring it
>> the whirlwind one will bring it
>> and it will and it could bring it very
quickly I can't put any limitations on
on God. But but we also
>> for those of you that are like the
whirlwind, what? Go back to the back.
>> Go back to back at the basics. And we'll
probably do a Sabbath school on that. I
think that a refresher would be great.
>> We need to do a current I can't that six
years ago. Wow. We need to do a current.
>> Yeah.
>> Freshen it up a little bit.
>> And I will say this, it is just as
relevant today as we did it six years
ago.
>> Yes. More relevant today.
>> More relevant today.
>> Yes.
>> Um I think back then there was more, oh
that's not going to happen. Oh, you know
the
>> right
>> as you see these things unfolding today
in the political world and the the
uniting of Christianity with politics
>> um particularly on the right
>> um the the defying of political figures
and the defying of of um positions as
>> uh okay you're a Christian if you stand
for these you check mark these things.
>> That is trans Christianity,
>> right?
>> That is not real Christianity,
>> That is that is a counterfeit version of
what an actual Christian is.
>> And so,
>> as we understand, Oh, yeah. Absolutely,
Wendy. And the and the Matthew 24 series
as well,
>> they all go hand. Look, you might as
well just take you a little, you know,
people do the streaming and watch like
>> all these shows and all that stuff.
binge watch.
>> You can binge watch Back to the Basics.
Binge watch um uh Matthew 24.
>> Binge watch the Project 2025 series, The
Elephant in the Room.
>> Yeah,
>> just
>> Yeah.
>> Go have get some popcorn.
>> And now, yeah, I'm [clears throat] going
to bring something up that I wasn't even
planning to bring up here, but I've
brought up once before. So, I am getting
ready and maybe we but I definitely but
maybe we you and I,
>> okay,
>> are getting ready to [clears throat]
to do a [cough]
an a Friday night study
on
the T horns in
>> Is it a Friday night study?
>> A Friday night study.
>> That's why you said May. May.
>> Yeah. On the T horns.
>> Guys, I get tired on Friday night. But
>> in Daniel chapter 7.
>> Okay. And the reason why this study on
Daniel chapter 7, the ten horns
is absolutely
>> I like Candace's idea. Do some shorts.
>> Yeah. On the on the on the
>> what you're mentioning right now. Yeah.
>> No, I think she's talking on the back to
basics.
>> Oh, back to basics. Okay, Candace. Yeah,
that's a good idea.
>> And Tik Tok. Candace, I need I need your
Tik Tok so I can see what you're doing.
>> Yeah, you got to train us on how to do
it properly. Okay.
>> So, um, the T horns.
>> Now, you might be like, well, what do
the T horns have to do with what's going
on in America today?
>> Absolutely
everything.
>> A lot of people and particularly within
our church, you know, see the United
Nations and they're off on a what's
going to happen in the United Nations
and they are so
>> far off the mark.
of what these 10 horns how these 10
horns relate to what's going on today.
It is honestly
it's a study that I have not been I have
not been hesitant I've never been
hesitant to do a study. This one I am
very hesitant to do
>> talk
>> just because I know like if y'all
thought
>> oh
>> the reaction to anything else I've done
in the past you know
>> she gets a lot of reaction.
>> Yeah. You know uh if y'all thought you
know the whole
uh
>> don't even say the word
>> anyway. Yeah. But I will say this
>> that it is absolutely crucial
>> you know when we when we when we look at
the 10 horns of Daniel chapter 7 we
typically focus on the 11th horn that is
the little horn
>> and you know we'll say yeah three were
uprooted and you know and that's it
>> we have been missing
I think perhaps the
most
significant
>> piece of prophecy.
>> Um,
and listen, I'm I know I'm I know I'm
building this up, but there are people
that I that I shared this with in my
Daniel in seven days class that we did,
Daniel in seven days.
>> And you Yeah.
>> And
they will verify,
>> right? I don't know if anybody's
watching right now, but they will verify
>> Yeah.
>> that this study on the T horns
>> is unlike anything they have ever heard
>> and absolutely essential,
>> right,
>> to understanding what is going on today.
So, plug for that is over.
>> Yes.
>> But there somebody said we somebody got
scared. They were like they thought you
did it last night. They're like I missed
it. No, it's it's [clears throat]
coming. Uh, actually I was slated to do
it last night, but that's before we knew
we were going to be in Texas.
>> Oh, that's before the baby decided to
come. Okay.
>> So, it will happen. It will happen.
Perhaps next Friday or the Friday after
that. We will see.
>> We will see.
>> Um, okay. So, but but back to this point
of of you know, Sunday law, a Sunday law
happening now. Yeah. this Heritage
Foundation thing say
>> it all it's doing is it's showing us we
have not believed cunningly devised
fables.
>> Yes,
>> that's all it's doing, right?
>> it so no project 2020 when project 2025
first came out, right? And I started
talking about it um
>> and I I said time and time again, listen
guys, project 2025 is not it. It is
showing us what they're thinking
>> but it's not gonna happen time. And then
when other people start talking about oh
project 2025 they got no no they are not
it it cannot happen. Why? Because it is
still only human power
>> right and human power is not going to be
enough to convert the atheist the Muslim
the secularist
>> you know the Buddhist. It's not going to
do that. So again, all this is doing
right now is it's showing us
where things are headed.
>> And and something something interesting
is happening right now, which I hadn't
even thought about before. I was just
thinking about it as you were talking
>> is there's becoming a move now within
Christianity
um that is anti-Israel.
>> Yes.
Huge.
>> Yeah. Huge. And it's pretty significant
because
>> I kind of take deeper dives in this than
you do.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I don't say like
I spend quite a bit of time
>> Yeah.
>> just seeing what's going on.
The reason I'm bringing that up is
because I think that if it's not
necessary for this anti-Israel sentiment
to grow,
>> but if it does, I can see, cuz someone
asked a question, well, why wouldn't we
why wouldn't we still be able to keep
our Sabbath? I don't understand. Right.
Um,
>> if this anti-Israel sentiment continues
within Christianity,
>> then with that would be an anti-Sabbath
sentiment
>> as the Sabbath is considered Jewish.
>> Yes. Considered considered Jewish.
>> Now, again, it's it's not Jewish. The
Sabbath is for everybody,
>> right? But again, I can see if this
anti-Israel sentiment continues to grow
within Christianity, it is another block
in setting the the stage right for a
rejection of the seventh day Sabbath and
the acceptance of a counterfeit Sabbath
>> in its place. Again,
what will ultimately bring that to pass
will be something miraculous,
>> something supernatural, not not a law
from the government,
>> right?
>> Not a recommendation from Heritage
Foundation or Turning Point USA or any
other foundation,
>> the whole world and even all of America
to be on board. All of America must be
converted.
after the order of things,
>> right? Yeah. And that's that's quite the
that's quite the that's quite the the
miracle.
>> Yep.
>> Quite the miracle that everyone's going
to come together.
>> Yeah.
>> And think a certain way. People are
putting links. Our our team is putting
links. The elephant [clears throat] in
the room.
>> Yeah.
>> We can brush all of these off. Really,
honestly.
>> Yeah.
>> For what's going on now.
>> Yeah. Um
a alarm towards the end towards the end
of the election cycle, the alarm about
project uh 2025 started going off. You
were doing it like two years prior to
that and but more people were joining in
and and talking about that. Um but
this has just been setting us up for
what is trying to happen right now.
>> Yeah. Again, these are the final
movements, but that whole
um project 2025, everything that they're
wanting to do is just
is starting to happen right now. And I
shouldn't say starting because they've
already done several things, but this
aspect of the 900 plus document,
>> um they're on the move right now. This
is what they're wanting to wanting to
get a lot of things done this year.
>> Yeah. Why do they want to get a lot of
things done this year? Because the
midterms are in November.
>> So between now and November,
>> they have the votes, if you will, to do
some things.
>> Yep.
>> And and I will say this, [clears throat]
this is why you guys, it it is so
important that we do not cry wolf,
right? Because the more you cry wolf is
the less effective
>> when it's actually time to say wolf.
>> It's a le you've you've watered down the
wolfing,
>> right?
>> And when we kind of go off on tangents
on, you know, this is prophetical and
this is prophetical.
Um
yeah, uh Renee, there are stages to the
Sunday law, right? So they will start
off mild at first, but the mild starting
off is under a particular is within a
particular context.
>> It doesn't start off mild without that
supernatural thing happening first. If
you read the great controversy,
um she literally says that it is Satan
who encourages the Satan in his
appearance as Christ
>> that encourages the world to observe
Sunday because he's the one that's
changed it.
>> Right. That's where the mildness begins.
>> Right.
>> Right. So it's under a under the
disguise of Satan as Jesus and mildly in
a mild mannered I'm Jesus. But that
mildness will ultimately lead to a death
decree.
>> These are the stages of that Sunday law.
>> It's not like the Sunday law passes, you
know, first and then gets worse and
worse and worse and then Satan appears
and then makes it really bad. No.
>> Right.
>> No. the secular people, atheists are
going to say,
>> "Yeah, no, we're not doing this."
>> Right?
>> This is not happening.
>> Okay? And the only people that will be
standing in opposition to this are those
who honor the seventh day Sabbath.
>> Not anybody else, not the skeptics, not
those who honor the seventh day Sabbath.
That's who the controversy is going to
be between, right? Those who keep the
commandments of God and those who do
not. So
>> I want somebody said something that like
just because I think because we brought
up uh the Jews and somebody said I've
noticed that why is everybody against
the Jews? And I want to say cl just to
clarif clarify that
and I can't speak for everybody but what
what a lot of stuff that's out there is
not about the Jewish people
>> specifically but um
um they are talking about Israel the
administration or
>> Zionist and you have to go deeper into
that. So um that movement so um
>> so whether whether that's justified
right or not like it's never justified
to hate to hate
>> or you know any group of people. So
let's take that off the table. But in
[clears throat] a lot of people's mind,
they have justification,
>> right,
>> for hating a particular group of people,
>> right?
>> Let me come back to this crying wolf
thing,
>> when we go off on tangents,
>> right?
That because remember now, yeah, I'm I'm
bringing it up without care and without
fear. Mhm.
>> Remember how COVID was going to lead to
the mark of the beast
>> and how the the shutdown of the church
was going to the mandate of the the
mandates were going to lead to to the
rise of uh of uh you know communistic
just all this stuff.
Where where are we now? We're in 2020
the vaccine the how it's going to change
your mind. all these things that that
that [clears throat]
we caught a whole lot of flack for for
not being on board this this train
>> of oh this is the beginning of the
government
>> bringing in draconian measures to do x y
and z.
No
>> see
>> all of that all of that you guys was a
was a was a was a rabbit was a rabbit
hole. All of that
was an absolute diversion that
unnecessarily brought division into the
Adventist church. People not talking to
anybody. People not talking to one
another one another because because
what? Here we are now on the other side
and all the oh this is going to lead to
more more this and more that and and
this and this and and church is going to
be shut down everywhere and this is just
the beginning. This is the dress
rehearsal.
>> No, no. When we don't understand
prophecy,
>> we will have a tendency to make
everything prophetic,
>> right?
>> And and everything now has prophetic
significance and that was prophetic and
cop 26 and cop 27 and cop 28 and this
and that and the pope what he did and
all of these things are distractions.
Meanwhile, Meanwhile, the thing that we
ought to be paying attention
>> attention about,
>> we're paying attention in the wrong way.
We're encouraging. We're supporting. Go
get the book. We're supporting. Go do
this. Go. We're supporting. They're on
our side. We're supporting. You know,
let's let's do things with them.
>> And we need to Yeah. No, I'm here with
you. I We need
>> It's absolute craziness.
>> It is. And we need to make
>> And it weak I'm sorry. And it weakens
the integrity. blessing, joy.
>> It weakens the integrity of the true
Adventist message.
>> And we need to make noise as 7day
Adventists like use our voices because
and to highlight these things like I
mean God would use a donkey and he's
using the Associated Press, you know
what I'm saying? Or ABC to bring this
out what's going on. Um because right
now, currently, if we're really doing
news in the Bible right now, everybody
is focused on what happened in Minnesota
a few days ago, which was a tragedy. Um
and you know, but everybody's focused on
that right now. And it's like, yes, AP
and ABC News is doing this or or put
that out,
>> but who's paying attention to it?
>> Yep. We I mean we need to be
highlighting this on our social media to
our friends like hey this is going on
like they're trying to do things in the
dark but not in the dark you know just
while just not paying attention to it.
So let's you know just quickly and
they're going to be make be making many
quick moves during this year again
because this is their span of time that
they feel like they have and they think
like after November they're probably
gonna lose control. Mhm.
>> Not of the White House, obviously, but
>> that's what they fear.
>> But
>> so we got to do what we got to do.
>> We got to do it all the things that they
want to get done. See, the reason why I
wanted to go back to the um the Jewish
thing because we brought it up and
somebody said, um, "Aren't aren't aren't
they talking about them because they're
God's chosen people?"
No, that's not why because they're no
longer God's chosen people. They were um
at at in in the Bible at the time before
Jesus came, but after Jesus died on the
cross that and it it the message went to
the Gentiles. Um they are no longer
God's chosen people.
>> Yeah.
>> We are.
>> We're spiritual Israel.
>> Yeah. And I'm going to say this. I'm
going to kind of give an example.
>> I'm going back to the crying wolf thing.
>> Okay.
>> Again,
>> I want to give two examples. Okay. Um,
[clears throat]
two two types of of shooting,
>> two types of of approaches to shooting.
>> Shotgun,
>> the bullets scatter and go everywhere.
You can hit things that you didn't mean
to hit.
>> Sniper,
>> the shotgun approach is a is a is a is a
waste of
energy, if you will,
>> right? And you may hit things you didn't
intend
>> to hit.
>> When we when we approach prophecy with a
shotgun,
>> we end up injuring or bringing injury to
the cause that we didn't intend to.
>> Nobody intends to bring injury to the
cause, right?
>> But you weaken the message,
>> right? because you now have people
chasing the the different, you know,
fragments of the shock of the of the of
that bullet that's going everywhere.
>> You got people running chasing rabbits.
>> God has called us to be snipers when it
comes to prophecy,
>> right?
>> Not not not a shotgun approach.
>> Boxing.
>> In boxing, you don't want to be throwing
wild punches.
Right? You don't want to just be like
you. A boxer wants to
>> he's going to conserve energy and he's
gonna he's going to hit he's going to
try to make every hit count.
>> If you're just throwing punches, you
know what's going to happen? You're
going to wear yourself out.
>> You're going to wear yourself out. And I
think what's happened over the last
[clears throat]
10, 15 years
is there's been a lot of
wild punches when it comes to prophecy.
>> We look stupid.
>> We look reactionary.
>> We look like we're trying to make
everything fit. And when you try to make
everything fit in prophecy, then nothing
fits in prophecy. Mhm.
>> If everything is prophecy, then nothing
is prophecy,
>> right?
>> Every little thing that happens.
>> That's right.
>> So, when we don't understand, here's how
the events unfold. Here's what's
happening. What happens is we we begin
running on tangents, right?
>> Tangents about secularism and communism
and Marxism and and and and
COVID and We run through all of these
uh rabbit trails.
>> Mhm.
>> Meanwhile,
so now all everybody's looking at, oh
yeah, what what's going to happen next
with the vaccine?
Ah, are y'all watching?
>> While we're looking over here, the devil
is doing his thing over here.
>> Nobody's paying attention. Not only
we're not paying attention, but when we
do see it, we're like, "Yeah, that's
just political.
>> So, I'm not going to focus on what
what's happening there because, oh,
that's just oh, you're ju you you're
just being political. No, let's focus on
what's happening over in Europe,
>> right?
>> Oh, look at the United Nations. Oh, and
the church's connection with the United
N." And we're we're looking at all these
things that I'm telling you,
>> it's like do it's like following a fad,
>> right? What is the latest fact that we
can follow? Now, I will guarantee you
right
>> that
>> there will be people who are like this
Heritage Foundation thing, this is it.
Sunday law is right around the corner.
>> And even then,
>> it's still not the worldwind. It
>> it's not the whirlwind.
>> And I think some people might say, "Oh,
okay. Well, some people focus on the
United Nations, but you're focusing on
the Heritage Foundation and Turning
Point USA and what they're doing." Um,
but like with United Nations,
they're not a spiritual organization.
>> No.
>> Where these two organizations that we're
talking about,
>> the United Nations is not in the Bible.
>> Right. Right.
>> The United Nations organization is not
in the Bible.
>> The the teaching that the United Nations
has some part to do in a in a evil
prophetic plot
>> is a teaching that originated with
Jehovah's Witnesses.
>> Absolutely. How have we how have we
how have we taken a Jehovah's Witness
talking point and made it part of our
prophetic scenario? Go read the great
controversy. You're not going to find
anything in there about an organization
called the United and it wasn't called
the United Nations then, but it was it
was I forget what the name of it was
before it became the United Nations, but
still go look at our pioneers and what
they said about the United Nations when
it became the United Nations. Go look at
Adventist ministers and and and and the
church uh uh um going to United Nations
meetings back then in the uh um
>> in the mid 1900s. Like
look at the articles that we've written
about being present at this United
Nations meeting. The United Nations
talking point of prophecy
was
originated
with Jehovah's Witnesses. You cannot
find the United Nations in Bible
prophecy. I challenge you.
>> And this is why that study on the T
horns becomes so critical and so
important
>> because a lot of us don't even
understand. That's right, Nicole. Then
the League of Nations, I think that's
what it was called before.
>> A lot of us do not understand and we
have borrowed prophecy
>> from [snorts] our uh our Christian
counterparts,
>> right? Whether they be Jehovah's
Witnesses or Baptists, Methodists,
futurists, we've borrowed prophecies
from uh there was a book that I when I
first became an Adventist,
>> there were three books. One was called
Behold a Pale Horse.
>> That was a hit book in the in the, you
know, Christian world.
>> Super conspiratorial,
>> but was dealing with Revelation and
Daniel a lot.
>> And as Adventists, I didn't realize it
wasn't an Adventist book.
>> Somebody put the sham god.
>> The sham god. That's right. But I would
read these books uh you know uh uh um
the new world order and and all these
read these books and just devour them
and without realizing it was putting
these views into mingling them with the
Adventist understanding of prophecy cuz
I saw I saw other people doing it
>> right
>> so they would talk about the United
Nations. I be like, "Oh yeah, United."
Of course. Of course.
>> Go to the Bible to the Bible alone.
>> And when you understand prophecy from
the Bible alone,
>> 90% of the of the stuff that is going
around now about this is prophecy just
suddenly become irrelevant.
>> Yeah.
>> They're just rabbit holes that you don't
need to like stay focused.
>> Correct. I almost want to put a
challenge out there like I put put a one
in the chat if you have read
all of the great controversy.
>> Yeah.
>> So the challenge is pick up the book.
There's people who like you've heard I
don't I don't know many of you probably
have heard David Ashik's story like he
found that's
that I don't know my mom told me that
when she was pregnant with me. She read
the whole great controversy for the
first time. She's been raised Adventist.
She was 27 at the time and that's what
really
>> converted her to be like okay the things
I was raised believing
>> I'm putting the pieces together now so
okay the ones are great
>> and for those who can't put a one and
even for those with the ones go do a
refresher you know so you know just go
do a refresher but um those who can't
put a one pick up the great controversy
yeah so that you have
>> and I would challenge you to to read
through it right and and while you're
reading through Look for Marxism. Look
for the warnings against Marxism,
against communism, against uh the United
Nations.
>> Look for these organ. Look for these
warnings and you're not going to find
them.
>> You'll find a warning against atheism in
in the French Revolution chapter, but
all this other stuff. Look for the
warnings against, you know, the the the
prophetic warnings against what the
vaccination would do. Look for all these
warnings. Not gonna find them.
>> That's a good question. I don't
Someone's asking is there a great
controversy version written in modern
day English? I don't know. But what
about the
>> Well, the great controversy is I mean
modern day English I mean
>> it's not written in the
>> it's not it's not like the King James.
>> Yeah.
>> But they're just making it like make it
just a little bit more
>> um the DVDs not DVDs. People don't say
DVDs anymore that
>> you just the audio books.
>> Yeah, the audio books. Yeah, you can
listen to you can listen to it audio.
>> No, but the one that was just done. It
was just sent to you last week.
>> Oh, I Yes, we need to talk about that.
>> But we had we had Sebastian on talking
about it. So, it's it's out now.
>> It's It is out now. And I'm supposed to
actually be promoting that. [laughter]
>> So, here we are. Here we are promoting
it.
>> Not Not We'll promote it. We'll
>> officially officially Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> So, Clive, if you're watching,
>> I'm Sebastian. Uh, weren't they all do
that? That's what I thought.
>> Yeah. Um, so so but anyway, that is why
it is so important you guys to not cry
wolf, to not throw useless punches, to
not throw to not use a shotgun approach
to prophecy, but a sniper approach to
prophecy because you lose people,
>> right?
Not intentionally,
>> but you lose people to rabbit trails.
You lose people to, well, you said this
was prophecy and that didn't turn out to
be
>> right.
>> We've got to become more responsible
>> with the way that we share prophecy and
the way that we understand prophecy
because a lot of us just aren't
studying. And then when we're not
studying,
>> either they're sharing it
either incorrectly or if they're they're
not sharing it, it's because they're
afraid.
>> Yeah.
>> And you don't have to be afraid. God
doesn't give us a spirit of fear. And
even though prophecy has a lot of
nuances here and there and all of this,
still the basis of the story is Jesus.
Yeah.
>> He's going to be victorious. We don't
have to be afraid.
>> Um but you know what? Look, you look at
take all the things that are happening
even with what Heritage Foundation is
doing, even what Turning Point USA is
doing. All of those are like those are
helping points. Like if we weren't like
our current political system and
situation and environment actually makes
it easy for us to share these things.
Yeah. If this was like
>> late 70s, early 80s, maybe not so easy.
You'd be like that's what you're saying
is absolutely crazy. But now, right now,
currently, you start sharing prophecy,
you're not sounding very crazy at all.
>> Yeah.
>> And you got the ABC and the AP to back
you up.
>> And and and then I'm going to say this,
right? So, I think
like there's a comment about the the
United Nations and, you know, should we
be a part of it
>> or not?
>> I I I think that question is neither
here nor there. And let me let me say
why.
Mhm.
>> Anything that is going to cause us to
compromise our doctrinal positions,
>> right,
>> we should not be a part of.
>> Absolutely.
>> Right.
>> Period.
>> The Bible says be in the world but not
of the world.
>> Right? So
the world is the world,
>> right? There are many organizations that
that churches partner with to do things
that may not be uh that may be secular
organizations,
>> right?
>> You cannot exist in a world and not
mingle,
right? Be the salt of the earth. Mhm.
>> So I think sometimes we put we put these
kind of like the Jews in the days of
Jesus was like well you know right never
mingle with the with the Gentiles
>> that we ought to know that
>> right
>> because the Gentiles are evil right
>> I think we can we can come to a place
where we start imposing evil right in a
way that is unbiblical. Mhm.
>> So the Gentiles were evil, the Greeks
were evil. Make sure that we don't
mingle with them.
>> Um, anything that that requires us to
compromise our belief system, no, we
should not be a part of, right,
>> any such thing that's going to require
us,
>> right?
>> But what I'm what I'm trying to say
particularly with the United Nations is
>> the the reason there is a there is a
hate for the United Nations is not
coming from secular people. Mhm.
>> It is coming from religious people who
have been taught that the United Nations
is an evil organization attempting to
bring about a one world order and that
is why
>> right it's not oh you know the people of
the United Nations are you know they did
this bad no it is the United Nations is
the organization that is going to try to
bring about the no war order and that's
why we as Christians You're not going to
find secular people, atheist people
saying, "God, the United Nations, we got
to be aware. Be be No. This is a
Christian talking point,
>> right?
>> That many Adventists have adopted, not
realizing that is not part of our
talking point,
>> right?
>> This is not the 10 toes of Daniel
>> chapter 2. This is not the 10 horns of
Daniel chapter 7.
>> They were not talking about the United
Nations as an organization. Daniel 2 and
Daniel 7 is referring to something that
is
so far beyond an organization called the
United Nations.
>> But anyway, I don't want to, you know,
harp on that.
>> Bottom line, guys, is this. What we've
just seen today from the Heritage
Foundation, from ABC News,
>> yes,
>> it is it is designed to help us in the
greater scheme of things to help us see.
We've not believed commonly devised
fables.
>> Amen.
>> Our critics are wrong in thinking, "Oh,
this is never going to happen."
>> Absolutely.
>> And we have to be able to see and
understand and not get caught up in
these false in these winds, these false
prophecies
that are
bringing in division
>> when we all should be on the same page
as to here's what we're looking for. We
know what we're looking for. We've read
it in Daniel in Revelation in the great
contract. Why are we now changing our
focus to Marxism? And why are we now
changing our focus to communism? Why are
we not changing our focus to to co
vaccines? And why are we not changing
our focus to to to to the trans what
what we know what we're supposed to be
looking for,
>> right?
>> Let's lock in on that. We're not saying
these things aren't, you know, aren't
significant in any way, but what we're
saying is prophetically speaking,
>> here's [snorts] what we're supposed to
be locked in on.
>> Let's not lower the trumpet on that.
>> Right.
>> Right. So, at the same time, at the same
time,
>> we're not saying, "Oh, yep. It's Sunday
law is now. It's coming to pass right
now." No. Because we understand Bible
prophecy. We're not overshooting and
we're not undershooting, right? We're
saying here's where we are. Here's
what's to come. No need to panic, but we
must stay alert and ready and not be
caught off guard and not be going down
rabbit holes.
>> Okay. And yes, Katie, some are saying,
"Pastor, please do more.
>> Stick to the script." I like that.
>> I like that, too. They're saying,
"Please do the Sabbath. Do more Sabbath
schools and connecting current events
events." And we will. We're going
through the series, the Christian Art of
War, because it's important. You know
what guys, the Christian art of war war
is just as important as this, but we can
we're going to have a variety of Sabbath
school. We can do this. We can do
Christian art of war. We can ask answer
your questions. Yes, that's going to be
really the basis of all the Sabbath
schools moving forward unless we have a
personal testimony coming in. Those type
of things. Um because even though this
prophecy stuff is spot on, we need to
know that if if if you don't have God
working in your heart and you get and
the the Christian art of war principles
are not uh your character and how you're
living your life, it doesn't matter
what's going to happen because
[clears throat] you're not going to be
ready for the kingdom. So all of it is
important, but thank you. And I do agree
that we do need to do more world news in
the Bible for Sabbath school because
things are just happening, especially
this year. we're gonna especially this
year um because that's what they they
say they they want to do. And I just
want to say this because I want to make
sure that we're being sensitive on all
levels because we've brought up just
using the terminology transgender quite
a bit. Don't ever want to offend
anybody. uh transparency. One of our
closest dearest family friends to myself
and to pastor to my mom that's been such
a big blessing in our life on so many
different levels is currently um living
the trans transgender lifestyle. Um but
uh
>> who is the one that I was talking with?
>> Exactly you were talking I like who are
you talking to? Okay. But she's such an
amazing person. her character um is just
a she's a be has a beautiful character
that's so loving and kind and literally
will give you the shirt off your back.
It's like like lit her the shirt off her
back and um yeah and she's one of our
viewers all the time uh for our many
Sabbaths. She's one of our viewers and
and she loves what we're doing here at
Living Matter Church and and God is and
God is working on her heart. But I just
I just want us to be uh not just to to
her because she knows our heart. She
knows we're not talking about that, but
just in case there's anybody else out
there that might hear those things
>> and and I and I have to say, you know,
the the point that we were discussing,
>> you got it from her.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Well,
>> you know, it was like, well, what is a
Christian and how are you getting that
definition wrong?
>> And it was like, wow,
>> there is trans Christianity. Yeah.
>> And it is, you know, in in the Christian
mind, oh, it's crazy to to when you're
to be a man calling yourself a woman or
a woman calling yourself a man.
>> Well, it is just as crazy
>> to not be living the life of Christ, not
be living the Christian life, and yet
call yourself a Christian,
>> right?
>> TransChristianity.
>> All right. So, yeah,
>> pretty simple.
>> Pretty pretty simple. So,
that's it for today. That's it for
Sabbath school for today, guys. We are
not done with church, but we are just so
thankful that you tuned in. Thank you
for doing this Sabbath school with with
us. All so many comments, uh questions,
all those different things. And uh we're
going to pivot back to this. We're going
to keep an eye on it, if you will. You
keep an eye on it, too. And please, when
we do this, when we come back to this
topic, uh as things are happening and
moving, please uh bring what you have to
bring to the table as well. This is
Sabbath school and we want to to hear
your comments and your thoughts and
feelings. But we have a message
>> that
>> so the message is entitled the hidden
kingdom. And this is a Bible study you
guys that um again is
uh it is going to give you an
understanding that you may have never
had before
>> on the kingdom of God.
>> Amen.
>> And uh I'm excited to go through this
study with you. So, please let people
know like um share with them, hey, this
the sermon's coming up, the hidden
kingdom. Um and I'm walking you through
>> the process of what Jesus meant when he
said, "Seek ye first the kingdom of
God."
>> Um and his righteousness, and all these
things shall be added onto you.
>> Amen. Amen. Share. Invite somebody to to
church. Subscribe to the YouTube channel
that you're on. and uh yeah just and
like there it goes like share and
subscribe those three things and we will
see you in the divine worship service
but we're going to pray first.
>> All right let's pray. Heavenly Father,
thank you Lord for giving us an
opportunity Lord to share um your word
uh today. Lord, thank you for um helping
us to understand that we have not
believed commonly devised fables Lord.
>> Um Lord, as we continue our service
today, please bless those that that will
watch that um that are watching now. And
I pray especially for the message today,
Lord, um on the hidden kingdom, Lord,
that you would speak to our hearts,
Lord. Help us to understand uh the
righteousness that is necessary Lord um
for your people to have and uh we thank
you Lord again for your love and your
grace towards us all. Bless us is our
prayer in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen.
In the most southern point of the
beautiful Hawaiian island chain is a
sacred spot that only a relative few
have seen. It is a hard destination far
from the paved easy road. In fact, the
journey requires more than a standard
vehicle to make it. Only a four-wheel
drive is tough enough to carry you
through the rocky [music] and rugged
terrain.
But these rugged roads bring you to a
must-sea island gem, the secluded beach
of Papa.
It is a glorious geological gem. In
fact, some [music] people call it the
Hawaiian Diamond, the green sand beach
of Mahana. Yes, the sand doesn't just
appear to be green, [music] it is
actually green. And there are actually
only four of these rare green sand
beaches in the whole world. Norway,
Guam, Galapagos, and here in beautiful
Hawaii.
[music]
These green glassy crystals are actually
called olivine. It is a rare mineral
that is characterized by its green olive
tone. It comes from the surrounding
tough ring. Now, tough ring is a
geological term that describes a small
volcanic cone surrounding a shallow
[music] crater. Many years ago, this
cradle was formed by aggressive
explosions triggered by hot lava rocks
clashing with the cold liquid ocean. The
dramatic [music] explosions blasted
fragments of bedrock, minerals, and ash
hundreds of feet into the atmosphere. As
the particles fell back to the ground,
it created this tough [music] ring. And
over the years, as the ocean waves clash
against this tough ring, erosion takes
place. The water washes the lighter
black volcanic ash out to sea, but the
heavier olivine settles to the ocean
floor and is pushed to the shore,
creating this rare green sandy beach
beauty. It is one of my favorite places
in all of Hawaii. And if you're ever
blessed to visit, please look, but don't
take. Far too much has already been
taken from these sacred Hawaiian lands.
It's more important for us to preserve
and protect these natural wonders so
that future generations can enjoy them
as well.
In order to see the majestic tough rig
and walk upon the green sand beauty, you
must be willing to traverse the rugged
and rocky road. For the way to Mahana
Beach is not smooth and easy. There are
many obstacles along the way. Rocks to
overcome, ditches to avoid, and hills to
climb. The way is windy and dusty. But
being able to walk upon the glorious
green sand beach is worth [music] every
step of the journey.
And my friends, the journey to heaven is
the same way. God never promised that
the path to perfection would always be
peaceful. He never said that we would
never encounter obstacles. In fact, he
said that the way to life would be
narrow and difficult. And just like the
green sand beach, only few there be that
would find it. But though he said it
would be difficult, he did promise us
that it would be worth it and that he
would be with us every step of the way.
So go ahead, venture up the unpaved
paths of sacrifice, the rough ways of
surrender, the steep hills of humility,
and the rocky roads of charity.
And as you do soon and very soon, you
will be able to walk upon the green sand
of heavenly glory. And on that beautiful
celestial shore, you will discover that
just like the sands of Papa Beach, that
the blessings of God cannot be numbered.
And the love of God cannot be measured,
but it will be ours to [music] enjoy
throughout the ceaseless ages of
eternity.
>> [music]
>> We hope you've been blessed and inspired
by [music] this new Reflections of Hope
episode. This episode is one of many
that's been produced all over the world.
If you haven't [music] done so yet,
please give our video a like, share it
with your friends, and please follow us
on Instagram, [music] Facebook, and
YouTube. If you'd like to see more
inspiring episodes and get access to
much more uplifting content, please go
now to patreon.com/revelationof [music]
hope and sign up to be a member of our
Patreon page. Your monthly support will
not only give you [music] early access
to many more inspiring videos, but it
will also enable us to continue to
produce more [music] of these cinematic
object lessons from nature. Our goal is
to produce and release these episodes
much more frequently. So, please
prayerfully [music] consider partnering
with us so that we may continue to share
the hope of Jesus all over the world.
Thank you so much for your support.
Aloha and Marinata.
>> [music]
>> Heat.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
It's so good to see you again here at
Living Mana Church on this beautiful
Sabbath day. Please put in the chat
where you are viewing from. Tell us your
name, your uh location, what you know,
state you're viewing from or country. Uh
we love to see that to see where all of
our viewers are viewing from. And if it
and if this is your very first time,
please put a one in the chat. We want to
tell you all about Living Mana Church
and how you can stay connected. Uh we
are just so happy to see all of you. And
if this is your if you've been here
since Sabbath school, then you don't
have to put your lo, you know, where
you're viewing from. Um but if you're
just joining us for the first time,
please put it in the chat. Um, so again,
we can say a very special welcome to
you. I don't know about you, but I loved
Sabbath school because we were talking
about current events, how it plays into
the Bible and and in prophecy, and it's
just always exciting and I could see and
feel the excitement that you guys were
feeling as well because it's so
relative. It's like, all right, things
are happening and this is uh not
something this isn't any conspiracy
theory. This is exactly what the Bible
uh is saying will happen and it's
starting to happen. It's not the final
thing. Um but it's it is time for us to
wake up and to pay attention and like we
said in Sabbath school to focus to to
refocus our focus on the things that
really matter. So again, please put in
the chat where you're viewing from. Want
to say a special welcome to you. Um got
okay Vancouver Island again. Welcome
Jodie. always good to see you here at
Living Mana Church and you're also one
of our uh faithful board members of
Living Mana Church and we just thank you
and also a lead leader in um in our
school L I always say it wrong. I always
say Elmo Moses but El Moses school uh
that we do here at Living Man Church and
you're one of the leaders that make that
happen. So we thank you for that. Um as
well we have Barbara who is watching
from Mississippi. Welcome Barbara to
Living Mana Church. It's good to see uh
you here.
Always good to see all of you here from
all around the world. It is such a
blessing. And as you guys can see, I
didn't mention obviously we are not in
our uh our main studio. We are on the
road. And we are on the road because we
um our daughter had our third grandchild
this week. And it's just such a blessing
to be able to be here with uh our our
newest grandchild and his siblings. So
now we have two grandsons and one
granddaughter. Uh and it's such a
blessing to be able to spend time with
them. Um but also be able to be here and
worship with you on Sabbath as well. All
right. Our locations are coming in a
little bit slowly today. So I might just
surpass that because they're coming in
slowly. But if you want me to say a
special shout out and a welcome to where
you are viewing from, you have a few
more seconds to put it in the chat uh
before we just start going to our other
announcements. All right. Well, there's
Paul. Hi, Paul. Welcome from Ottawa. And
I believe that's Canada. So, welcome.
Love how many um Canadians and British
um British Columbombians that is. Yeah.
From that we have here always on uh
living mana church. such a blessing.
Also, we have Georgia and Sammy from
Chrisfield, Maryland. Welcome. Happy
Sabbath. Um, we have um Barbados.
Welcome. Good to see you here. This is
wonderful to see. And then we have
Christie from South Carolina. Welcome to
Living Man Church. Good to see you here
as well. Well, I want to We I didn't see
anyone. So all of you have been here
before. So you know about living mana
church but just in case you have not
connected to living mana church yet. I
want to just remind you on how to do
that. So if you want to stay connected
to living mana church and help us to
stay connected to you. You can sign up
if you are in North America to get text
alerts. So you can just text LMC to
855207-4107
and then you will get the alerts and
when we're going live usually about 20
minutes before we go live can remind you
of different things that are going on in
the church and this is so helpful
because we are all so very busy. We have
so much going on in our lives and so who
doesn't need a text reminder? I know I
need a text reminder and uh my husband's
the pastor of the church. So if I need a
text reminder sometimes, I'm sure you
do, too. So you can get that if you are
in North America by texting LMOC again
to that 855 number. So as you know, we
are 100% online church and so our
viewing audience is from all around the
world. Literally as I'm speaking I'm
seeing somebody put um in the chat that
they are viewing from um let's see from
Nambia right so that's all around the
world this is where we are but if you're
viewing from all around the world or in
another country that's outside of North
America um then you are going to need to
sign up for Mighty Networks and even if
you're in America you need to sign up
for Mighty Networks because again Mighty
Networks is our virtual home this is
where community um is this is where we
form community here at Living Manit
Church. These are where our small groups
are established and they meet there. You
can meet the leadership of small groups.
You can see all the different small
groups we have going on and you can join
one of them. You can and you can just
fellowship in Mighty Networks and reach
out and connect and it's just so amazing
what can happen there. So Mighty
Networks is in the chat. you can
download that link so that you will be
able uh to sign up for that and just be
a part of that into the living mana
church family and just have find so much
community there and so that's through
mighty networks. Also just want to
remind you guys that we do have
children's programming. That's Locosc
Kids meets at 11:30 Central time on Zoom
and you can text kids to that 855 number
and someone from the leadership team
will reach out to you so you can get
your child or if it's a niece, a nephew,
a grandchild, uh just somebody's, you
know, somebody else's child, they can
you can share this information with them
so that they can get their children
signed up for LMOC Kids. And I can tell
you that LMOC kids, they are learning um
just at their um level of understanding,
their age level, they are learning some
of the deep things in God's word just
like you are. They're having lots of fun
doing it. And we have a great team
that's dedicated to uh LMLC kids. So
please, if you want to sign up your
child or if you want to share this
information to get somebody else's child
signed up, please do so. You can do the
email or you can text kids to that 855
number.
Just want you to know that Pastor Meyers
does have virtual uh virtual church
office hours. So if you're needing to
speak to Pastor Meyers, you can do that
and to schedule appointment by uh
emailing Patrice at living.live.
And so you can set up a meeting to speak
to Pastor Meyers. If you want to become
an official member of LivingMana Church,
you can do that by using that email
patrice livinga.live.
If you are a member already of of a 7th
day Adventist church, you can transfer
your membership. If you are learning
about what Seventh Day Adventists
believe from the Bible, um, and you want
to become a member, but you don't feel
like you need to be get baptized again
because you've already been baptized
before, you can join by profession of
faith. Or if you feel like, I would like
to get baptized um into the Seventh Day
Adventist Church or maybe even
rebaptized, you can send an email to
patrice livingmana.live
and pastor Myers, Pastor Myers will
baptize you. Um, and so you can again
just send that email to patrice
livingmana.live and she will get the
ball rolling. So that is how those are
the three different ways that you can
become an official member of living mana
church.
Also I just wanted to share with all of
you about true health Tuesday. Now we've
had this program ever since we started
but we currently um and we always have
amazing people from Dr. Schwelz to Dr.
Reynolds, they've all been amazing, but
we currently have had Dr. Maria Joseé
Hume, who's been absolutely amazing. I
was watching one of them this week, or
actually, I saw one of the clips, I
think, on Instagram, and it took me back
to the original thing that she did. And
this, you guys, this is something they
say, um, uh, maybe young people would
say this, just this is something we used
to say in the world. Uh, we used to say,
don't sleep on, you know, XYZ. When we
say that, that's kind of just like a
kind of terminology that means when you
say don't sleep, like don't take it for
granted what the information we're
sharing on True Health Tuesdays and I'll
even say mental health Mondays. I mean,
we're sharing some great stuff. And Dr.
Maria Jose, when it comes to nutrition,
guys, tune in. Tune in. She has some
great stuff. That's every Tuesday at 700
p.m. Central time. It's been a blessing.
I know that I, you know, took some of
her things that she was sharing from a
couple of weeks ago and was like, "Yeah,
I'm gonna apply this to my life as
well." And I think you're going to find
some really um amazing things. Like,
yes, we all need doctors and health
professionals, but there's a lot that
you can do for your body, for yourself
just by the choices you make and what
you eat. So, that's True Health Tuesdays
every Tuesday at 700 p.m. Central
Standard Time. And if you sign up to get
text alerts or for Mighty Networks, you
will be reminded of um this program.
Also want to encourage you and remind
you about the power line. The power line
is one of it's the second of our prayer
services on Wednesdays by our prayer
team here at Living Man Church. And the
power line is designed a little bit
differently. um our our power
Wednesdays, it's for everybody, but it's
also, you know, a lot of our in-house
people are members that are already here
come to that where the power line is for
those who uh don't know about Living
Matter of Church or maybe they're not
members and they don't come all the
time. They just are just they just need
prayer and they just uh want somebody to
pray for them. The power line is for
that. And when they come to the power
line, you or they can put their prayer
request in the chat and our team will
pray for them right then live. Whatever
they're going through right then,
they're going to be prayed for. So, you
can actually share this uh link with
them and say, "Hey, every Wednesday at
8:00 PM Central, our power our team on
the power line prays for whatever
requests come in right there live." Not
I'll pray for you later. No, I'm we're
praying for you right now. So, you can
share that with a friend, with a
co-orker, family members, and just let
them know that they can get their
prayers prayed over uh immediately. Even
if they don't want to put it in the
chat, you can do it for them, and they
can just listen and be blessed to hear
someone praying over
their request. All right, so I also want
to let you guys know that we like to
have fun at Living Mana Church as well.
We have a ministry called Hangouts.
Hangouts has been so much fun. uh and a
blessing to be able to be a part of.
Hangouts are all about kicking back,
having fun, and enjoying time together.
Think of it as our chill spot. Whether
we're watching something, playing games,
or just hanging out, it's a chance to
connect and laugh outside of the usual
rout routine. No pressure, no agenda,
just good vibes with good people. If you
want to be involved in hangouts, I would
I would love for all of you to be
involved in hangouts because we want our
community here at Living Mana Church to
pray together, study the Bible together,
cry together, love each, you know, love
on everybody, but we also want to have
fun together. And if you are interested
in that, text Hangouts to 855207-4107
to get reminders so you will not miss
out. You can also scan the QR code that
is on the screen as well. Also want you
guys to um remind you about the glow
groups. Glow groups are small digital
gatherings where we dive deep into
pastor's sermons and the word of God
together. These groups are designed for
real connection, thoughtful study, and
joyful fellowship. Members also began
using photo theology chat GPT to play
Bible games to explore scripture in
fresh interactive ways. And for a side
note, Pastor Meyers um he actually built
and produced the chat GPT um game or app
so that you can be able to participate
in that way. Um, if you are interested
in joining first for or starting one of
[clears throat] these housefires, email
group living mana.urch.
Let's grow, glow, and keep and go deep
together.
Also, we have a ministry, give mana, and
that's led by sister shaine. Give mana
is our space on mighty networks
dedicated to outreach and inreach
ministry. It's designed to make
connecting with resources simple and
meaningful. Whether you're seeking help,
offering support, or pointing someone to
the right place in their local
community, um this is this is how you
can help find and coordinate local
resources, share guidance, and direct
others to support in their area.
Together, we make sure no one has to
walk alone. Join give mana today and be
per and and um be per and all right just
join living give mana today um and also
just be a part of that ministry and they
are looking forward to having you there
with them. Want to give you guys
announcements. You may have seen that
the LMLC youth uh grow the L the LMLC
YouTube has seen some growth lately.
we've had more subscribers subscribing
and I want to tell you a little bit more
about that and how that is happening. So
from October to December, our our
YouTube channel exploded with growth.
Subscribers surged from 7,000 to 46,000
views, skyrocketed from 300,000 to 2.9
million. This isn't just numbers, it's
impact. This is a real measurable growth
and the beauty is you can track it
yourself. Every donation you make as has
a direct uh visible impact. You're not
just giving, you're fueling results. You
can actually watch unfold in real time.
In the past, even our most popular
sermons average 1500 to 2,000 views.
With our new strategy, those same
sermons are reaching 150,000 to over
200,000 views. That's 10 times more
souls reached. And these aren't just
Adventist viewers. We uh that are
watching. The unchurched and unbelievers
are also watching. People who may be
hearing the gospel for the very first
time. Why this matters? Nearly a quarter
of a million people watch sermons on
Hellfire and on Sabbath. Our content is
showing up in reels like a digital track
and the numbers prove they are clicking,
watching and engaging. The challenge
ahead is we are aiming for 10,000 new
subscribers every month reaching 1550
50,000 subscribers by next year. Imagine
the lives touched if we can sustain this
pace.
Why we need you, our Living Man Church
family. Strategic marketing has fueled
this growth, but it's but it isn't free.
Here's the difference your giving makes.
For every dollar spent, dozens of people
hear the gospel. A gift of $100 helps
reach thousands of viewers with
truthfilled content. Your donation to
the local budget is an investment in
souls reached, sermons heard, and truth
shared across the globe. Coming soon, a
special line item in Adventist Giving
will be dedicated to this mission.
Together, we can keep the digital doors
open and extend our reach even further.
We will you stand with us in this
challenge. Remember to watch your giving
in action as our numbers grow. So, we
are just excited to have the capability
to be able to reach so many people. So
continue to keep that in prayer and give
as the Lord is leading um on your heart.
Also just want to remind you guys about
Eli Global um and what that is because
we can go all around the world but we
want to go around the world in the
different languages of the world. And
currently right now we're doing that in
seven different lang languages. And this
is just a little example of what that
looks like.
Blue.che.
is
back.
for
amazing what technology can do to make
it seem like we speak all these
different languages. anguages. We
obviously do not, but it is a blessing
to be able to um have the messages and
like you saw that was a Sabbath school
that we did uh together and it looks
like we both speak Ukrainian and we
don't but the technology allows us to be
able to do that and currently right now
we're going uh in seven different
languages but we want to go into more
different languages. So, if you would
like to support or continue to support
what Living Mana Global is doing, just
want to let you know how you can do
that, you can go to adventistgiving.org.
This is where you can give your tithe
and your offering online that supports
Living Mana Church, but you put you go
to adventgiving.org.
You put in Living Mana Church. a virtual
tithe envelope uh falls down and you can
see there you can give your tithe which
supports the northeastern conference uh
which Living Matter Church is um a part
of the Northeastern Conference and it
will go to support the conference and
the worldwide 7th Day Adventist Church.
When you give to the local church
budget, that stays here with Living Mana
Church. It helps us to do all the many
things that Living Mana Church is doing
um just to be able to operate on the
level that we're operating. As you see,
we're on the road uh so we can have a
studio on the road uh if if need be. Um
and it helps us to be able to get all
that equipment and all those things that
we are needing. as well. We have a
benevolence fund that helps people who
uh reach out who are in in need
assistance, need financial assistance.
We are able to help them. Um and that's
coming from the benevolence fund. So, if
you want to give to that and so many
different other areas that you will see
on that virtual tithe envelope, you will
be able to give and to support Living
Mana Church. If you do not want to give
virtually or online and you would like
to mail in um your tithe and offering,
you can do that and uh by sending it in
to uh the PO box that you see there on
your screen, you will be able to do
that. The PO Box 428, Owens Crossroads,
Alabama 35763.
When you do um send that in, please just
put a little note, send a note with it
to let us know how much is for tithe,
for offering. If you're wanting to give
to the benevolence fund or something
else that you see on that tithe envelope
you want to support, just let us know so
that we can make sure uh that your
giving goes to the area that you want to
support. We are so thankful. Uh I said
this last week, but we are here in 2026.
That is amazing. Elm Living Man Church
is about to in April on April 9th going
to celebrate our first our fourth
birthday. It is our I should not say
birthday anniversary. Fourth anniversary
of but I mean I could call it a
birthday. I mean the living mana church
was birthed and we're still here. So,
all right, our birthday, but it's the
fourth anniversary of Living Mana
Church, and we are so excited and just
so thankful to God for this was just a
thought, a thought in Pastor Meyer's
mind that I know and believe it came
from God. And he that God has just
really allowed this to be um as as
amazing as it has been. And we know that
God is wanting to make it better. So
every year we want to get better and
better, better with our programming,
better with our technology. We want to
reach more people. This is why Living
Mana Church is here. And we're
international. So we want to reach the
whole world. And again, we want to reach
them in the languages of the world.
That's why we have LMC Global. But we
are just so thankful for all of your
prayers and your financial support,
showing up, sharing the link, talking to
your friends. It is not us. It is not by
ourselves. This is not Pastor Myers and
and I that we can't do this by
ourselves. We have a whole amazing team
in so many different areas that do what
they do to make this happen. And then we
have you make this happen as well
because you share, you talk about it. Um
again, you share the videos, you let
people know that we are here. And so we
are so thankful for what you do. But if
you would just please bow your heads
with me as we pray and just give a
praise of thanksgiving, a prayer praise
of thanksgiving to God at this time. If
you would just bow your heads with me as
we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I just want to
thank you for the Sabbath. want to thank
you for all the viewing audience that is
so supportive of Living Mana Church and
praying for this church, praying for our
family and there's and and just um just
praying us through all the different
things uh that we go through. Lord, I
want to lift them up at this time and
just ask that you uh will will bless
them. Lord, there are so many that are
listening that are going through uh
family uh struggles and issues. It could
be with their marriage or raising
children or might have a sick loved one
um and they are just needing prayer just
for for courage to be able to face what
they are going through. Um Lord, I want
to pray healing for those who are sick
that you will bring healing into their
bodies. Lord, give them peace that you
are with them even as they are going
through this time. Lord, some are
struggling with finances. they are not
they don't know where the money is
coming from. Lord, I pray that you will
give them peace that you hear their
prayers and you're going to take care of
them, Lord, in the way that you uh do
the things that you do. Lord, uh but
Lord, I'm praying a financial blessing
for them as well. And Lord, there's some
that are not um employed and they they
need a job. Lord, I pray that you will
bless them with the job that you want
them to have. Some are just crying out
to have a closer walk with you, Lord.
And I I know you will answer that prayer
for them. you answer that prayer for all
of us. Lord, I just want to lift up
Pastor Meyer's message uh that you have
given to him for today. I pray that the
Holy Spirit will just be poured out upon
all of us who are listening. Um just
give him the words to say. We ask all of
these things in Jesus name. Amen.
There comes a moment in every life when
the ache [music] of this world is too
great and the questions become too loud
to ignore. Is this all there is? What
happens after this? Will life ever be
more than this?
What if heaven is not the end of your
story
but the beginning of your greatest one?
What if perfection does not mean [music]
stillness but limitless growth?
Endless reinvention, infinite
creativity, joy [music] beyond fear, and
connection beyond imagination.
What if heaven is [music] a place where
every sense awakens and every dream
expands?
You were not designed for boredom. You
were not created for collapse. You were
not born for endings. You were made for
infinity. Join me for an experience that
will reshape how [music] you see God,
eternity, purpose, and your future.
Because once you understand heaven, you
will never live the same on earth again.
Register now at the
mastermindstitute.com/heaven. [music]
Again. Theminstitute.com/heaven.
[music]
Step into the destiny you were meant
for.
How much does [music] Jesus love us?
More than words can measure, more than
our minds can comprehend.
From the very beginning, love was his
plan. Romans 5:8 [music] says, "But God
demonstrates his own love for us in
this. While we were still sinners,
Christ died for us. He didn't wait for
us to be worthy. He came when we were
lost, broken, far from him. That's the
love of Jesus. Not distant, not
conditional,
but personal, real, sacrificial.
A love that moves him to call us his
own. 1 John 3:1 [music] reminds us to
see what great love the Father has
lavished on us. That we should be called
children of God.
No sin too deep, no pass too heavy,
no heart too far gone
because his love reaches beyond every
[music] boundary.
Jesus loves you fully, freely forever.
I'll be [music] more loved
right now. Wasn't holding you up. So
there is nothing I can do to let you
down.
It doesn't [singing] take a trophy
to [music] make you proud.
I'll never be more [singing] love than I
am right now.
Going through a storm, but I won't
[singing] go down. I hear your voice
carried in the rhythm of the wind.
[singing]
Call me out.
You would cross an ocean so I wouldn't
drown.
You've never [singing] been closer than
you are right now.
Gyra
Gyra, [singing]
you are enough.
[music] Oh [singing] J,
you are enough
and I will [music] be content
in every [singing] circumstance.
You are
you are enough.
I don't want to forget
how I feel [singing] right now on the
mountain top. I can see so clear what
it's all about.
So stay [singing] by my side
when the sun goes down. [singing]
Don't want to forget how I feel right
now. [singing]
Gyra
you are enough. [singing]
Oh Gyra
you are enough. love [singing]
and I will be content
in every circumstance.
You are gyra.
You are enough. [singing and music]
I'm already love.
I'm [music] already [singing] chosen.
I know who I am.
I know what you [singing] spoken.
I'm already loved
more than I could imagine.
And that is enough.
I'm already love.
I'm already chosen.
[music] I know who I am. [singing] Yeah.
I know what you spoken.
I'm already love
more than [music] I could imagine.
[singing]
And that is enough.
That is enough. What is truth says is
better than anything.
That is enough. I don't need money or
material things.
That is enough.
That is enough, [singing]
Lord. You are enough.
You are enough. [singing]
You are enough.
You are enough [singing]
to hold. You are Elra.
You are enough. [singing]
You are enough
[singing]
and I will be content
in every circumstance
that you are.
You are enough.
Here
at Living Mana, we bear each [music]
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to [music] face life
struggles alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Praise God.
>> Greetings. Greetings saints.
Always a blessing to be here you. Happy
Sabbath. We'll be uh facilitating this
sacred time of prayer today and we thank
you. Thank you. Thank you for allowing
us to be uh participate in in in this
part of worship and and service today.
I'm Danny Clark. This is my other lovely
half, Jackie Clark.
>> Amen.
>> And we're so blessed to be here with you
today.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> And we're sitting on behalf of our
leaders. I I I must always acknowledge
our leaders. God has gifted us with
>> a great man and woman of God whom we
just we're just so grateful. Brother
Terry,
>> and Sister Am. And I tell you, I'm still
basking. I had the opportunity to meet
with her last week face to face. We were
talking about that this morning in our
chat, how gosh, just the intimate
oneonone personal time we spent with
each other and and uh Shine and Denise
were with us, but I don't think I got to
sleep before 2 o'clock a.m. any morning.
>> But just to be able to have a meal
together, to share our experiences, and
it was just such a blessing. I tell you,
beautiful inside and out. And God has
really blessed us with some great
servant leaders. And
>> Amen.
>> Even though we hate to see them when
they're not here because we love them
and miss them dearly, but you know, at
least they have an opportunity,
you know, to continue to do things that
God has called them to do or, you know,
whatever is necessitated during this
time of their life. We're always happy
to stand in for them, but I tell you, we
always miss them in their way.
>> Absolutely. It's not the same, is it?
>> It's not the same.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah, we do miss their presence, but uh
we do pray for them. We want to keep
them lifted up as well.
>> Praise God.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Well, wow, there's a lot going on. Glad
to have you back. I'm glad I was glad to
see her. She went out and she just I
could tell she was having a great time
with these sisters. Amen.
>> They speak over the phone and and and
they finally got to meet one another
>> and it was a blessing. And I can tell
you right now, I know
>> I know my wife [laughter] They talked
and they were up late talking and they
enjoyed each other and they had a great
time. So, so bless these powerful women
of God and so glad to have my wife back
home and his home safe and everybody.
So, anyway,
>> so what's going with new with the prayer
team? What are we up to? We're always up
to something.
>> Always up to something. So, yeah,
because we believe so much
>> in the prayer,
>> the power of prayer.
>> So much that we're engaged right now in
a 10 days of prayer. And it has been
fire,
>> hasn't it?
>> It has been.
>> Today actually will be day four. We
started Wednesday night.
>> It will be day four.
>> Amen.
>> And it has been a blessing. And I'm
telling you, um,
>> these prayer warriors
>> unleashed. What a topic.
>> It is a topic unleashed.
>> Unleashed.
>> Yes. [laughter]
Yes. And And I want to take a moment.
I'm probably going to step out here and
do something here because um, but why
talk about prayer and not invite anybody
to pray?
>> That's right. So fine. So I'm gonna I'm
gonna put it out there. I don't know. I
don't have the link, but I'm going to in
ask and impose upon somebody out there
within our team to put that link in the
chair because I know we're going all
over the globe now. We want to reach
people with every moment that we can.
Yeah.
>> And uh and encourage
>> every night.
>> Every night
>> at 6:30 p.m. Central Standard Time.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. And uh and I think
[clears throat] it I think you'll be
blessed. I don't think I know. And we're
experiencing some great
Oh, wow. Can't even talk about it. It's
so It's just so much soularching.
>> Been a blessing to me. Yeah.
>> Soul searching. And I think,
[clears throat] you know, for myself,
>> I you know, God is call I know. I felt
I've been feeling that God was calling
me to higher heights and deeper depths
in him. And this of course means
shedding a lot of stuff as well, right?
putting away a lot of and I I believe
God that same message by the power of
his Holy Spirit, he's been sending that
out to a lot of people and
>> we are searching, we're crying, we're
calling out for it and we are doing some
self-examination and just surrendering
and I love it. Surrendering it is
powerful. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Yes, it's a it's a beautiful
thing.
>> And uh yes, please please invite one
person
>> and uh see what see how God uh moves on
your behalf. Amen.
>> I wasn't going to share this, but I'll
go and share it. [laughter]
And um I invited I invited my um
my daughter-in-law and my son. I said I
actually I sent it to my daughter-in-law
because I know she'll get my son to to
join in and uh and I shared this with
our prayer team and I just want to share
this. It really brought tears to my
eyes, you know, no pressure. I just um
I just sent her the link and I just, you
know, and my daughter, I said, you know,
we're having prayer uh every night.
We're have 10 days of prayer every night
at 6:30, right? Hey, would love, you
know, if you can, would love for you to
join us. and and I sent that the first
night that we got started. And then
Thursday night after I didn't see it
till Thursday morning, you because
[laughter]
after after our prayer meeting, I went,
you know, I I went to bed, but um or got
ready for bed and I didn't watch my
text, but my daughter-in-law sent me
this message. I wasn't going to share
it, but I I I will because [snorts] it
may encourage you to to uh to send it to
peop, you know, just send it to family,
to friends. Don't don't be reluctant or
hesitant. You know, you don't have to be
overbearing. Just say, "Hey,
>> amen.
>> We're having prayer. 10 days of prayer.
Would love for you to come if you're a,
you know, if you're available." But
Thursday night,
>> she sent this and I didn't see it until
Friday morning. And this was it Friday
morning? I think it was. She says, this
is what she said. She says, "As I was
getting ready for bed and reflecting on
tonight's prayer call, she did join.
I realized something. I wanted to say
thank you. Thank you for praying for me
when I didn't have the strength to pray
or know how to pray for myself."
>> Amen. Amen.
>> You just don't know the depth of what
this message meant to me. She said, "As
I sat in the hospital bed, blinded to
God's miracles
and grace that he had on my life." Let
me read. She says,
[clears throat]
she says, "Thank you. Continue to offer
that gift to others because prayer
changes things."
>> Hallelujah. Amen. See,
>> brothers and sist [laughter]
Oh my goodness. But it brought tears to
my face. You never know. And she's not
one to talk a lot, right? No. So, I know
she meant it. And and and I just I just
appreciate that. And so, brothers and
sisters, let this encourage you.
Sometimes we may want to hold back or
say, "Oh, no. They don't don't worry
about the outcome. Just move. Just, you
know, share with others because you
never know
what God can and will. God will always
work in behalf of his people, of his
children's lives." Amen. Amen. Amen.
>> So, I just wanted to share that. Sorry,
I got all choked up, but
>> that's a that's a mighty
>> mighty powerful praise. Amen. Amen.
>> And I just wanted to encourage you to
put your prayers in the chat. Brother
Danny has Danny has been collecting the
prayers on the u power of the lamb um
YouTube.
>> Not a whole lot, but we have some.
>> Yeah. And I collected them on the living
mana. And I just want to we and I just
want to call out here we have our prayer
warriors at their post um on power of
the lamb. Sister Pauline is there
collecting those prayer requests. Sister
Ayana is doing is um doing the live
prayer. Praise God for our these are our
prayer warriors folks. And s and
blessing sister blessing is doing the
encouragements I believe.
>> Thank you people all in the prayer
church. Thank you.
>> Yes. on the living manner. Sister Sheila
is collecting the prayer requests. Uh um
Karen Wright, I believe, is doing the
light prayer. And then Sister Joanne,
let's see. Oh, Sister Joanne and Sister
Karen are doing live prayer. And Sister
Barbara the encouragement. These are our
prayer warriors. And I and and if we if
you can get a prayer request in, please
know that our prayer warriors are
collecting these prayer requests and
they are prayed over all week praising
God for that. And want to encourage you
to to continue to send in your praise
report. I do have praise reports after
this. Continue to send in your praise
reports. I I tell you, you see how that
praise report for my daughter-in-law, I
got all choked up. But it's a blessing
to see how God is moving, how God is
reaching the hearts and the lives of his
people and uh and just praising God and
and again it's an encouragement to
others uh to have faith to hold on until
their change come. Sometimes I know we
can pray and maybe wonder if God's going
to ever answer my request. Yes, he is.
>> Amen. God just want you know and
sometimes he just want us to maybe that
holding on is is the testing of our
faith so that he can show I've never
left you nor forsaken you and that's
right
>> so I want to encourage you when God have
answered prayer
>> it's a sending in your praise report is
a way of glorifying God and revealing
his power his love and his strength in
the lives of his people is also a way of
encouraging others especially those who
may be be waiting for some time you know
to get their prayers answered amen
Amen.
>> Did you have anything to add to that?
>> No, I'm just listening to you. You're
doing wonderful. [laughter]
>> You can tell who the talker is in the
family, right? [laughter]
>> Hey, let me say something. People think,
"Dad, you're too quiet. Too quiet." I'm
capable of talking. Yeah,
>> I can run my mouth more than you know,
[laughter]
but I only talk when it's necessary, and
I try to say something. I'm not the
brightest and the sharpest person in the
room, but uh none of us are. try to
speak try to speak when it's needed and
say something of value and listen I'm
more of a listener to be honest with you
and I and I pride myself on listening
>> more than anything and uh but no this is
this is a little fun time between
[laughter]
anyway praise God it's good to be here
>> you said something very significant that
I have said something of value
>> and that is so important especially when
we're talking to others
>> Amen
>> that the words are laid face with
elegance, with love, with warmth and
value, you know, to always make sure
that when we say something that we want
to say something of value to others.
Amen.
>> Amen.
>> All right. Well, let's go to our praise
reports. We have a I've given one
already, my daughter-in-law. Praise God.
And um the first praise report we have
here is from Ayana. She says, "I I call
this a halo a hallelujah anyhow moment.
I left my purse with my wallet and house
key in a maxi on my way home. Too many
bags. And she has laughing out loud. You
know how we are. We got all these bags
and so many we we leave something
behind, right? And heaven forbid my
wallet in my purse. But one that I was
not familiar with, but [clears throat] I
decided to wait where I dropped off to
see if I would recognize. Wait a minute.
I think I've So she said, "Oh, I left my
purse and my wallet and house key in a
maxi on my way home. Too many bags. One,
so a maxi that she was not familiar
with." She said, "I decided to wait
where I dropped off where I was dropped
off to see if I would recognize the
maxi. Luckily, the maxi came back right
where I was waiting to see if he saw me.
All the money in my purse was gone, but
I got everything back. Thank God. It's
not perfect, but it's the best outcome
possible. I love how Sister Jana, she
said, "It may not be what I wanted. I
wanted everything right." Rightfully so.
But it was the best. She said, "It's the
best outcome considering." Praise God.
And this was is and still is Ayana. A
hallelujah moment. Sister Curls, I am so
sorry to reach out like this, especially
on your personal and she Oh, she was
just I think this was the note. I could
not find a prayer line email and hope I
would find some grace here. I am asking
for prayer for my daughter, Acacia.
She has taken an important test today at
5:30 that will help determine her next
steps in her educational journey. Math
is not her strongest subject. She was
she has already passed all the others
and saved this one for the last to give
herself more time. On top of that, she
is starting to feel sick today as is
just and is just out of it. But she is
unable to reschedule. I just needed to
reach out and ask for prayer
from wherever you are. If you are
unable, please feel free to pass this
along to anyone who can. I am and will
be doing the same. I would truly
appreciate it. Thank you so much for
understanding and I'm really sorry again
for reaching out this way. She sent this
out. I breathed to Amra and and it was
posted in our prayer chat for our prayer
warriors and this is the praise report.
She says [laughter]
update. Won't he do it? Hallelujah.
Somebody, anybody run back. Thank you
both for partnering with me in prayer.
And thank you to those who I don't know
of who paused and touched and agreed
with me in God's hearing.
>> In other words of my to my dear brother
Terry, my God today uh and sister so run
tell the praise report right here. Um
love you guys and all praises to our
most high God. She passed the test.
[laughter]
>> Hallelujah. Praise God. God is so good.
Oh, we're rejoicing.
>> We are rejoicing. I love I love Amen.
Yes. Praise God. And this is from
Pauline. Sister Pauline. She said, "I
[clears throat] just left my doctor's
office. My blood pressure is still
high." He said, "Gave me a prescription
for medication. He told me to take it
until the 28th because I was getting my
full physical by then. He will assess it
then. Please continue praying for my
blood pressure to decline. I praise God
for everything. Glory. Hallelujah. Thank
you, Jesus. The nurse was amazed that I
was talking this way. I said, "Girl,
you've got to praise him no matter what
you're going through. Do not let the
enemy think that our God is not with us.
Trust him." And and and family, this is
Sister Pauline all the time. She's
praising and always looking for the very
best outcome regardless of the
situation. Praise God. And this is
praise report. My blood pressure is
starting to decline. Praise God.
>> Amen.
>> Another praise report is I have a 9:30
interview today with my director for a
progressive housing coordinator
position. It is a salary position and I
will be working the day. So, I guess
she's moving. I think she's worked night
shift now. So, with this new position,
she's going to have a better shift, day
shift. Amen. Praise report. Thank you so
much for your prayers. I got the job.
Praise the Lord. [laughter]
>> See,
>> I can see her now. I got the job.
Hallelujah.
>> She's history.
>> Praise God. God is good. God is good.
Praising you, God, and thanking you,
Lord, for all that you do for us, your
people. God is a good God.
>> That is awesome. Awesome.
>> Love to love to um lift up and give
honor and praise the way it's due. But
we have a God that truly loves us.
>> He does.
>> Hears the prayers. He may not have have
answered yours yet, but his thing is
things are working out. And I just
believe in that. I believe in the prayer
>> for your good.
>> And that that said, we're going to go to
the throne of grace. If you believe in
the power and the transformative power
of prayer, let us join together right
now and go to the throne of grace. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Wow. My heart is just I'm just basking
in that praise right there.
>> Amen. God is good. Heavenly Father, let
us come to the throne of grace, Lord. We
humble ourselves
before you right now, Lord. And we give
it to you, Lord, in exchange for
blessings. And Lord, we know that you're
here, Father, if we have sent up praises
right now, Father, praising your name,
Father, uh for the blessings and the
prayers that you have answered thus far.
>> But Father, I want to take a moment,
Lord, and just uh uh give you our
hearts, Lord, and ask that you cleanse
us, Lord, of anything that's not like
you.
Father, we just uh we know that we can't
have odds and and things that that stand
between us, Lord, that'll hinder our
prayers. We want every prayer, Lord, to
reach the throne, Lord, in Jesus name.
>> Father, I thank you. Thank you for for a
praying wife, a praying partner, Lord,
the the opportunity to be here to
intercede on behalf of your people. And
father, we just lay every request Lord
at the feet at your feet, Lord. Trusting
in Lord that know we know that you're
here and we know that you have answers.
You've already shown that today
>> Lord in our lives and others
[clears throat] lives in Jesus name.
Excuse me. And Father, we just want to
continue Lord to let this type of set
Lord
>> Yes.
>> continue to move on behalf of your
people. And as we lift these people up
to you right now in the name of Jesus.
Father, I want to pray. Uh there's uh
some Leela Peterson. I have a prayer. I
don't have a lot folks, but I'm gonna
I'm gonna lift him up in the name of
Jesus. Amen. [clears throat] Lita
Peterson says, "Pray for Hunter. He's
opening to hearing about our church in
end time events." Amen. Praise God.
Amen.
>> Praise God. Heavenly Father, Father,
while the while the mind and heart is
open, Father, I'm asking you to move by
the power of your Holy Spirit, Lord.
Lord, may something be said and be
shown, Father, that will draw him closer
to you, Lord. This is necessary, Lord,
an interest, Lord, to hearing about the
church, the word of God, Father, and the
end times. Father, I pray that you will
position whoever that person may be.
Lord, we we pray there's something of
said, Lord, that will draw him closer to
you, Lord. Open his eyes that he can see
and ears that he can hear, Lord.
Manifest yourself in his life, Lord,
that he'll hunger and thirst and want
more, Lord. And ultimately, Lord, be a
servant of yours, Lord, and in
salvation, Lord. He's given his life to
you, Lord, and serve and to walk with
you, Lord, all the days of his life,
Lord. In Jesus name, Lord, I'm asking
you to protect him and keep him, Lord.
Lead and guide him, Lord. May his
questions be answered in full in Jesus
name I pray. Amen. [clears throat] Amen.
Cheryl Smith, please pray for my
daughter and myself. Father, we lift up
this precious par this parent and uh to
you right now. Father, thank you for her
being a praying mother. Thank you for
her love for for uh for her daughter and
her family, Lord. Father, we pray that
you will strengthen u strengthen them.
Strengthen them both, Father. And
Father, we pray that the old door will
be open, Lord. that her daughter Lord
will be will see and hear and know and
come to love and trust you
>> father in Jesus name. Father, we just
pray for whatever she stands in need of.
Father, we ask for her protection. Lord,
let her come to know and see I love
through the eyes of Jesus Christ, Lord.
And the ultimate ultimate thing and know
what love is like she'd never seen
before. Lord, only you can show her
that. So, Lord, we put that in your
hands
>> in the precious name of Jesus, I pray.
Cover them, Lord. Protect them, Lord.
Provide for their every need in the name
of Jesus, I pray.
>> Amen. Amen.
And father, I want to lift up uh at MT
pray for myself, for God's leading,
seeking to make a uh a geographical
change in his life. Amen. Amen. Father,
we pray that you will lead and guide
him, Lord. Open doors for this this
person, Lord. We lift him up to you by
faith, Lord. Asking in the name of
Jesus, Father, that you'll open up every
door, Lord. We pray that you'll go
before him, Lord, paving the way,
Father, Father, for a new position and a
new location, Lord. A better career,
whatever he stands in need of, Father.
You you you know his heart. You know his
desires, Lord. You know everything that
he stands in need of. So, Father, I pray
for his family, Lord. I pray for his
guidance. I pray for his faith to be
strengthened, Lord. I pray for his walk,
Lord, to be closer to you in the name of
Jesus. Father, uh, bless him, keep him,
and cover him, Lord, in the name of
Jesus I pray. Amen. [clears throat]
Father, I pray for Barbara Edwards.
Lord, please pray for my family to turn
to God. Oh, hallelujah. Father, thank
you, Lord. Thank you, Lord.
>> Yes, Father.
>> That's a mighty blessing, Lord. Father,
we truly stand in the gap with her,
Lord. Ask it, Lord. Salvation, Lord, uh
uh is is is most needed all over the
place, Lord. We all have that family,
Lord. We're trying to lift up to you in
the name of Jesus, Lord. Lord, we want
them to have the desire. We have the
desire for them to be saved, Lord. Lord,
>> covered, Lord,
>> looking and seeking eternal life, Lord.
We're in this world, but not of this
world. And help us be better leaders and
guide and give us the words to say, but
Lord, only you can change them, though.
So, make us a vessel and and uh help us
operate operate in that space, Lord, for
for you in a mighty powerful way, Lord.
and pray they hear it, Lord, in Jesus
name. Prepare their hearts to receive,
Lord. There are many people willing to
share that, Lord. But we know we live in
a world that's tainted, Lord. And your
word says people will deny and hear the
truth, Lord. They will turn from hearing
these ways. But Father, you are the
almighty God. We're asking you to prick
their hearts
>> and help them turn, Lord, and where the
door will be opened. And Father, there
are people will walk. They will share it
in the way you will bless them to share
it, Lord. So we ask that you go before
both of us, Lord, and and and use us,
Lord, for your glory. In the mighty name
of Jesus, I pray. Amen. [clears throat]
Christina 5791,
pray for families, especially the
children, teens, and young adults.
Hallelujah. Pray for those leading them,
Lord. Pray you. Thank you, Lord. Amen.
And father, I just want to lift up
those, Father, that have that
opportunity to to minister to our young
children and our teens and our adults.
Lord, this is why you have shaped and
fashioned us, Father, to be a vessel for
you, Lord, that we can go and make
disciples of people and and share the
word of God, Father, in the name of
Jesus. Father, I lift up every family,
Lord, that desires this, Lord, and want
their family and loved ones and and and
in their communities, Father, to be
blessed and come to know the loving
father Jesus Christ, Lord. And we just
pray that uh that you will equipped
>> and uh strengthen and guide, Lord, to
lead them to teach the childrens and the
teens, Lord. The children is our future
and they need to be equipped. So father
we just lift this prayer up to you now
in the name of Jesus to bless it Lord
and strengthen those father in the name
of Jesus. Bless thank you for this
prayer request in the name of Jesus.
Bless you sisters for having the love
and the passion to lift that up for the
prayer warriors and the love of God.
Amen. Amen. [clears throat] And uh
brother James 5382
pray for Rich recovering from open heart
surgery.
Uh we want to lift up his wife.
>> Yes.
>> Audrey and daughter Shay. Amen. Father,
we pray for speedy recovery. Lord, we
pray he's healing. We pray that your
hands are upon him. Father, we pray that
uh his heart uh is uh restored back to
normality, normality, [clears throat]
and functioning the way you designed it.
Father, in the name of Jesus, thank you
for those that that prepared to serve
you, Lord. uh uh pray that it's
continued to be a success, Lord, and be
with the family, Lord, and take away all
worry and fear and and uh and
[clears throat] uh uncomfortable
feelings and all these things that come
when when we're praying for a loved one
that have gone through surgery. Lord, we
pray for healing, total healing, Lord,
for brother James and his family. Lord,
or brother Rich.
>> Thank you, Lord, for hearing and
answering this prayer, Lord. In Jesus
name I pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. I got one more, Jackie, I think.
Amen. [clears throat] Sister Katie.
>> Amen.
>> And please pray for my mom's health and
uh and our and our cares and looking for
a different position. Careers, she said,
I'm sorry, I can't even write it. Pray
for our careers and looking for a
different position. Amen. Father, we
lift this request up to you by faith.
Lord, we pray for uh Katie's mom.
Father, we pray for her health. Give her
strength, Lord. whatever her heart and
body needs. Father, we pray your hand
will provide. We pray for the divine
healing upon on her Lord in Jesus name.
Father don't know the age but it doesn't
matter Lord just let her latter days and
dates going forth Lord be filled with
strength, power and uh good
[clears throat] health Lord in Jesus
name. And most of all Father may she
become to know, love and trust you in
the name of Jesus. Father, we pray for
their careers. Father, pray for that
advancement. Lord, open doors, Lord,
that no man can shut. Lord, place this
family in in position, Lord, to go
forward, Lord, and move, Lord, with
confidence in Jesus name. Because we
serve a loving God, Lord, that is
faithful and will. And when we when we
hear, he hears our cry, Lord, you answer
in the name of Jesus. Lord, thank you.
We praise you. We give you all the glory
in Jesus name. Amen. And amen.
>> Amen. You see cases seven
[clears throat] prayer request. She says
is that please pray for my friend Kayla.
Her father-in-law passed away this week.
Praying for the Holy Spirit to comfort
them in this hard time. Also she asks
for us to pray for the world that they
get to know Jesus. Amen. Sitta
Sitta [snorts] Small 6918.
My prayers for my children and family to
come to Jesus. Also, prayer for my
son-in-law who is sick with pancreatic
cancer. Regina Destiny says, "Please
pray for my mother's mental and physical
health. Steady her and strengthen her.
Revitalize me in your light, Lord.
Fortify me in your word." Hallelujah.
Praise God.
>> She also asks that we pray for people's
strength. Um, she said people are tired
for uh for toiling for their bread.
Strengthen and and ask us to pray that
God strengthen and keep them. Lisa Clark
says, "Please pray for traveling mercies
for my niece Heather." Amen.
>> Who is coming home from a work trip in
Paris
to Paris. Uh Mary Anne Weekes, I am
requesting prayer that I will make the
correct decision for this week coming
up. I praise God for answering my prayer
requests in the past. Please continue to
pray for me not to have anxiety. Kura
Washinga
9969 says, "My prayer request is for my
husband to accept the truth of our Lord
and Savior Jesus Christ, for him to be
the head of the family." Praise God.
Beautiful prayer request. Zadena
um-B7G,
please keep myself and my family in
prayer. I desire to go to heaven to live
and worship my almighty God continually.
I want need him in my life to consume
me. Oh holy spirit, consume me. Oh most
loving and gracious father, you have
heard the petitions of your people.
>> Yes.
>> And Lord, we thank you that you always
hear and you always answer. Father, I
pray that you be with Caleb and that
family who lost um
who father-in-law passed. Lord, death is
so it's so hard. is it is hard and
something that Lord we never ever get
over. But God, I just ask that you bring
the comfort and the solace and peace
that this family so desperately need.
>> Amen.
>> Be their anchor. Be their strength
physically, mentally, emotionally,
spiritually, as well as financially
because Lord, they're incapable of doing
this for themselves. But God, when they
can't even pray, Lord, I pray that you
read their hearts and knowing that those
hearts are crying out for strength and
comfort, keep their hearts and minds in
Christ Jesus, Lord, and protect them. I
pray God that that the enemy does not
allow this as a vulnerable situation to
cause others, your people to turn away
from you. But God, I know that in it,
regardless of what things are, you can
bring good out of all things. So,
Father, guide this family, keep this
family, protect this family, and comfort
them only as you can. Amen.
>> Lord, I pray for those that are praying
for We've had so many prayer requests
for family members, for husbands to come
to the Lord, for children to come to the
Lord. Lord, for our world to come to the
Lord. Lord, this is your world. These
are your people. everyone, even those
that don't acknowledge you. You you you
love them and is your desire that none
will be lost.
>> It is your desire to lose none. So,
Father, we lift them up before you right
now. And pray, God, that their hearts
are softened towards you. That the eyes
of their understanding that maybe has
been darkened, that the glory of the
Lord is revealed. And Lord, that the
scales fall from their eyes so they can
see you, see your love, see your power,
see your strength, oh God. And I pray
God that that eyesight will lead them
beyond those things that they see with
the carnal eye into more spiritual truth
and understandings. Oh God, I pray that
your loving kindness is drawing them
even now. I pray that the eyes I pray
God that their eyes are open to see the
length, the width, the depth, the
height, oh father of the great love that
you have for them and even and that love
that was poured out on the cross
>> for them. Lord, when you gave your son,
oh Lord, I pray, Lord, that they that
they come to you and they soften towards
you. Your words that through loving
kindness have I drawn thee. Lord, I pray
that each and every day they're able to
see your loving kindness. They're able
to see your goodness, Lord. Sometimes we
are blind to that. Even the little
things we neglect, where God, your love
is so poured out. Oh God, save them.
Sovereign hearts, God, continue to draw
them and move them into yourself. I pray
in the name of Jesus. Lord, I pray those
that are dealing with physical, mental,
emotional, Lord, healing and spiritual
healing. Oh God, deliver and set free.
Oh father, your children need you. I
pray God that you bring them into
emotional peace and balance.
>> I pray God that you give them that joy
unspeakable
Lord and that peace that surpasses all
understanding.
Lord, help them. Help them Lord to trust
you more. They don't need a lot of
faith, just a little bit. And God, use
that little faith, that mustard
seedsized faith that they may have. And
God, I pray that that let that faith
work miracles. Let that faith work
wonders, God, in the name of Jesus.
Lord, press into them. For those that
don't know how to press into you,
Father, press closer to them. And Lord,
let them feel your closeness and your
nearness like never before. Let them
feel the warmth of your breath and your
embrace as it just surrounds them and
huddle them close to your heart, oh God.
that would just
>> that would just calm and soothe the soul
and the heart that may be anxious Lord
that may be in chaos. Father, I cry out
for your children. Do what nobody else
but God can do. And Lord, Maryanne was
asking for asking Lord that you help her
make the right decision. Father, this is
so important. So important Lord that she
hear from you. It only takes one wrong
decision that Lord that we live a
lifetime of consequences for. So God
lead her, guide her. You know Lord what
the future holds. And Lord we know that
you hold our future.
>> Amen.
>> So God lead her in the way Lord and help
her to make the decision that's going to
have the results that you desire for her
Lord. The results that's going to be
favorable for what you have called her
into in the name of Jesus. Help her God
not to be anxious for anything. Help her
to trust you even with that mustard side
faith to put that mustard side faith in
you knowing oh God that you care for
her. Hold her hand guide her and lead
her God into the right decision that's
going to that's coming up this week
that's going to be best for her her
future for that of herself and all that
may be influenced by this decision.
Father I pray for husbands. Oh God, I
pray for families. Lord, I pray for
marriages. God, I pray God for marriages
that may not be worshiping together.
Father, I pray in the name of Jesus, you
can make all things right. Woo those
couple, Lord, woo them to yourself. Help
h help those that Lord, help those to be
examples of you in all their relation
with their family. Help them to always
lift up Christ until Lord, you move.
Help us not, Lord, go before you and try
to do what you have not called us to do,
but to be that example of your love and
of your light, Lord, before our family
members. And God, I pray that husbands
and wives and wives and husbands come to
worship together. Father, you know how
to draw. And God, I just pray that you
move you move upon hearts by your power
and by your love. Because Lord, your
love compels men. your love, oh God,
when it is seen, Lord, it leads us,
Lord, to follow you. So, Father, I just
pray that you just work in the Lord,
work in the situations of these family
dynamics, whatever they should be like.
I pray, God, that you break that you
heal the broken altars of families.
There may be unforgiveness. There may
be, Lord, there may be distrust, Father.
that may be uh children that have turned
their back on their parents or parents
are giving up on their children. Father,
I just plead reconcile these
relationships Lord in the name of Jesus.
But Lord God Christ given us the
ministry of reconciliation. Father I
pray for restoration for of forgiveness.
Help us to forgive. Help us Lord to
forget. Help us God to s to to to to to
not have hardened hearts towards
forgiveness. And God, we can't do it in
and of our own strength. We can do it
only through Christ who strengthen us.
So God, and maybe those that are having
difficulty, don't even know how to how
to reach out and cry out to you. Help
them, God, and show them the way. Show
them, Lord, how to be willing to be
willing. Show them, Lord, how to
forgive. Show them, Lord, how to trust
again. Show them, Lord, that you will
heal them from that hurt. You will bind
up their wounds and men their broken
hearts. Restore, oh God, these
relationships. Bring them back, oh God,
into a right relationship that is
healed, Lord. The healing that only you
can give, loving father, we thank you
for your goodness and your mercy and all
that you have done, Lord. And just
continue to pour out pour out your holy
spirit, Lord, upon Zadina, upon us all,
Lord. We want to be consumed by you. We
need to be consumed by you, Lord.
Consume us with that power. Rain down
from heaven upon us. Because Lord,
without your Holy Spirit, we can do
nothing. Lord, we're just vessels
waiting, oh God,
>> for you just to subdue these vessels
with your power, with your strength, oh
God, that we will love the way you love,
that we will have the compassion that
you have, God. that we will have the
longsuffering and the patience that we
will love you as we ought so that we can
love each other as we ought. Oh God,
subdue these broken spirits and minds
and hearts. Lord, help us surrender them
unto you to commit them God.
Surrendering all. I pray this Lord and
other mercies in the name of Christ
Jesus. As I turn this prayer back over
to my husband to pray for our pastor,
Lord, as he gets ready to bring the
sermon.
>> Amen. Amen. Father, thank you for this
wonderful time of prayer. Father, as we
transition into our divine service
today, Father, I lift up our pastor
before you, Lord. I pray that you will
cover him, Lord, and protect him, Lord.
And Father, just give him the power and
strength and faith, Lord, to speak
boldly upon your word today, Lord, to
bless the people, Lord. Feed your sheep,
Lord, with this word today, Lord. Let it
have convicting power, Lord, in Jesus
name. Lord, prepare our hearts to
receive it.
>> Yes.
>> In the name of Jesus, Lord. And Father,
we just thank you, Lord. We pray that
you cover him while he's traveling out
today. Thank you for getting him there
and bring him back home safe, Lord.
Praising you for all the new life that's
in this family right now, Lord. Thank
you, Lord, for this pastor. Lord, we
know he's been a trying time for them,
Lord, in the name of Jesus.
>> But, Father, we lift him up to you,
>> God.
>> By faith right now, Father, use him for
your glory.
>> Yes. and as you deliver this message.
>> Yes, God.
>> In the name of Jesus, I pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Amen.
[music]
Thank you, [music] Jesus. [singing]
for my [singing and music] words fall
short.
I've got nothing new.
How could I express
all my [music]
gratitude?
I could sing [music and singing]
as I often do.
But every [music] all of my stand
and you [singing] never do.
So I [music] lift up my hands and praise
you [singing] again and again.
All that I have is [music and singing] a
hallelujah.
[music]
And I [singing] know it's not
fit for a king
except for a heart [singing]
singing hallelujah.
[music]
I've got one response.
I've got [music and singing]
one move
with my arms stretched wide.
I will [music] worship you.
So I lift up my [music] hands and praise
you again [singing] and again.
Cuz all that I have is
[singing and music] a hallelujah.
Hallelu.
And [music and singing] I know it's not
much, but I've fit for a king [music]
except for a heart singing [singing]
hallelu.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
soul. Don't you get shy on me. Lift up
your soul. You've got a lion
[music and singing]
in the lungs. Get up and praise
[music and singing] the Lord.
Come sift
[music and singing]
up your soul. You've got a [singing]
lion inside of [music] those lungs. Get
up and praise the Lord.
>> [music]
>> Come on my soul. Don't you get shy.
[music and singing]
Lift up your soul. You've got a lion
inside of those [music] lungs. Get up
and praise [singing] the Lord.
[music] Oh come [singing] my soul. Don't
you get shy on me. Lift [music] up your
song. You've got a lion inside of those
lungs. Get [music] up and praise the
Lord.
Oh,
praise him
for your [music] holy name.
I will praise the name.
I will praise [music and singing]
the name.
I will praise the name
Jesus.
So I lift up my hands and praise you
again and again.
All that I have is a halleluj [singing]
[singing and music]
single
hallelujah.
man. Amen. Happy Sabbath, church family.
Um we are
getting ready to get into the living
mana for the day. And um I want to
invite you uh to first of all um if you
haven't invited anyone yet, please start
to do so now. We're about to get into
the word of God. I'm going to ask you to
put that one in the chat
[clears throat]
if you are ready for the living mana.
And um today's living mana is going to
be something special. It's going to be
something special. So um let's go ahead
guys have a word of prayer and then
let's let's um see what the Lord has to
share with us today. Let's pray now.
Heavenly Father, thank you Lord. Thank
you for your grace. Thank you for your
goodness. Thank you for your mercy. Lord
today,
Lord, as I share with um those
listening, those watching what you have
shared with me, Lord,
I pray, Lord, that you would make this
um very deep subject
simple to understand. But Lord, more
than simple to understand, Lord, I pray
that you would bring conviction to our
hearts.
And Lord, please
grant us
access
to that hidden kingdom. We pray in Jesus
name. Amen. And amen.
Um [snorts]
[clears throat]
once again everyone, the sermon uh title
today is the hidden kingdom. The hidden
kingdom.
And uh we're going to start with um a
very well-known verse spoken by Jesus in
Matthew chap 6. Matthew chapter 6 verse
33.
Matthew 6:33. I'm going to see if I can
get this up on the screen. Give me one
second you all.
Matthew 6 verse33.
Um Jesus says these words, "But seek ye
first the kingdom of God and his
righteousness, and all these things
shall be added onto you." It's a verse
that we all know and that we know very
well. Seek ye first the kingdom of God.
Seek ye first the kingdom of God and his
righteousness, and then all these things
shall be added onto you. Now typically
when we read this verse
um we we understand that the context
of this verse Jesus is speaking uh to
his disciples and he's and he's saying
that we should not worry about the
things that um that pertain to this
world. And in fact, I'm going to read to
you verses 25, and it's not in my
slides, but I just want to read to you a
little bit earlier uh just before Jesus
says these words. He he says this,
"Therefore, I say unto you, take no
thought for your life, what you shall
eat, or what you shall drink, nor yet
for your body, what you shall put on. Is
not the life more than meat, and the
body more than raignment?" So what he's
saying here is don't worry so much about
what to put on and what to eat. That's
what he's he's trying to get his focus
our focus on. He says, "Behold the fowls
of the year, for they sow not, neither
do they reap nor gather into barns, yet
your heavenly father feeded them. Are
they not much better than they? Which
one of you by thought can add one cubit
unto his stature? And why take ye
thought for raignment? Consider the
liies of the field, how they grow. They
toil not, neither do they spin. And yet
I say unto you, that even Solomon in all
his glory was not a raid like one of
these. Then he says these words,
"Wherefore,
if God so clothe the the grass of the
field, which is today, and tomorrow is
cast into the oven, shall he not much
more clothe ye, oh ye of little faith?
Take therefore no thought, saying, "What
shall we eat, or what shall we drink, or
wherewith shall we be clothed? For after
all these things do the Gentiles seek,
for your heavenly Father knoweth that
you need these things." And so, I want
you to understand the context here,
which is which is really quite amazing
because Jesus then follows up and says,
"But seek ye first the kingdom of God
and his righteousness, and then all
these things shall be added onto you."
And and we typically
we typically
understand that all these things shall
be added onto you to mean
that if we seek God's kingdom and his
righteousness, then we'll get the
clothes and the food that the Gentiles
seek after.
Beloved, I don't believe that this is
what Jesus is saying.
The all these things shall be added onto
you when you seek first the kingdom of
God and his righteousness is not limited
to
daily food and clothing. There is
something much deeper going on here. We
are being invited
to seek the kingdom of God.
That is a very powerful invitation.
In fact, it's a commission.
It's a calling. It's a life work. It is
the highest calling that one can
receive. Jesus has invited us to seek
the kingdom of God. And now guys, I want
you to understand why why this is so
powerful. Because
the question becomes, how do we seek the
kingdom of God?
How do we seek the kingdom of God? And
Jesus answers this question
in John chapter 3. In John chapter 3,
Jesus is speaking to Nicodemus.
And he says, the Bible says, "There was
a man of the Pharisees named Nicodemus,
a ruler of the Jews. The same came to
Jesus by night, and said unto him,
Rabbi, we know that thou art a teacher
come from God. For no man can do these
miracles that thou doest except God be
with him."
And Jesus answered and said unto him,
"Verily, verily, I say unto thee, except
a man be born again, [clears throat]
he cannot see the kingdom of God."
Nicodemus saith unto him, "How can a man
be born when he is old? Can he enter the
second time into his mother's womb and
be born?"
Jesus answered, "Verily, verily, I say
unto thee, except a man be born of the
water and of the spirit, he cannot enter
the kingdom of God. That which is born
of the flesh is flesh, and that which is
born of the spirit is spirit. Marvel not
that I said unto thee, you must be born
again. The wind bloweth where it
listeth, and thou hearest the sound
thereof, but cannot tell whence it
cometh." and wither it goeth, so is
everyone that is born of the spirit. And
then John 3 uh verse verse I'm sorry,
let me read that again because I want
you to understand this in its context.
John 3 verse 8. The wind bloweth where
it listeth,
and thou canst not or when when thou
hearest the sound, but thou cannot tell
when it cometh, whether it goeth. So is
everyone that is born of the spirit.
Jesus is saying here that that you
cannot tell the origin of the wind or
where the wind ends up.
It's mysterious.
You cannot tell its beginning nor its
ending. And then he says, "This is what
it is like to be born of the spirit."
Okay, so we've just read a lot here.
Jesus says, "Except a man be born again,
he cannot see the kingdom of heaven."
Think with me now. Jesus said, "Seek the
kingdom of heaven." And then he tells
us, "Except a man be born again, he
cannot see
seek
see the kingdom of heaven." All right,
y'all put a one in the chat if you
following me so far. Jesus says, "In
order to seek the kingdom of heaven,
you must be born again because only then
can you see
the kingdom of heaven.
Are you with me so far? Now please
please note with me. Uh uh Jesus also
says except a man be born of the spirit
he cannot enter the kingdom of heaven.
So so to see and to enter the kingdom is
one and the same. Those who are born
again are able to see the kingdom and
thus are able to seek the kingdom. And
in seeking the kingdom, they are in
essence entering the kingdom. Now,
here's what I need you to understand as
we set the foundation for this message.
What is the kingdom of God? The book of
Hebrews, the book of Hebrews, chapter 8,
verse 1 and 2 tells us this. Now, of the
things which we have spoken, this is the
sum. We have such a high priest who is
set on the right hand of the throne of
the majesty in the heavens, a minister
of the sanctuary and of the true
tabernacle which the Lord pitched and
not man.
Bible is telling us here that we have a
high priest who is currently in the
heavens and as a minister of the
sanctuary and the true tabernacle which
the Lord pitched and not man. In other
words,
in other words, what I want you to see
and understand here, and we'll read it
again in ma in Hebrews chapter 9:4. For
Christ is not entered into the holy
places made with hands which are figures
of the true, but into heaven itself now
to appear in the presence of God for us.
What I want you to understand, beloved,
is that heaven [snorts] itself, the
kingdom of God,
had a symbol or a type on earth. And
that symbol or type was the tabernacle
or the holy places made with hands. All
right. So to recap then,
Jesus says, "Seek the kingdom of
heaven." But we cannot seek or see the
kingdom of heaven unless we are born
again. Those who are born again can both
see and enter the kingdom of heaven.
We've now learned that the kingdom of
heaven had a had a prototype had a type
which was the Old Testament sanctuary.
The Old Testament sanctuary therefore
would represent the kingdom of God. In
fact, in Psalm 77:13,
the Bible says here, "Thy way, oh God,
is in the sanctuary. Who is so great a
God as our God?" Now, if we were to take
a look at that Old Testament sanctuary,
you'll see it here on the slide in the
screen. You will see that the sanctuary
itself, the tabernacle itself
contained two compartments called the
holy place and the most holy place.
These compartments consisted of four
articles of furniture. They were the the
uh seven branch candlestick,
the table of showbread, the altar of
incense, and then in the most holy place
was the ark of the covenant. In essence,
beloved, these four articles of
furniture represent the kingdom of God.
Okay everybody, I'm going to ask you to
go ahead and put a five in the chat if
you understand the connections that we
have made so far. The kingdom of God
in type
was represented by the earthly
tabernacle
which was divided by holy place and most
holy place.
They had four articles of furniture. It
had four articles of furniture. the
candlestick, the table of showbread, the
altar of incense, and the ark of the
covenant, which had the mercy seat.
These four articles define the kingdom
of God.
And it is quite interesting, beloved,
that you might remember David in the Old
Testament spoke about how the world was
so messed up and how the wicked seemed
to prosper. But he could not understand
why this was so until he entered into
the sanctuary. Then he had greater
understanding. In other words, what the
Bible is telling us is that those who
have access to the kingdom of heaven,
those who are able to see and thus seek
and thus enter the kingdom of heaven
which was typified by the tabernacle on
earth. Those who are able to enter into
this place have greater understanding of
how God operates in life. Greater
understanding of how God operates not
only in the earthly realm but in the
heavenly realm. Let me ask you a
question. How many times
has something occurred to you? How many
times have you seen things happening on
this earth? seen things that seem
unfair, unjust, and wish that you had
greater understanding, wish that you
could see the workings of God. And what
God is telling us here is that those who
who seek the kingdom of God, those who
are born again
will by the grace of God have greater
understanding of how God works, of the
wise behind God's doings.
They will have greater understanding
of the ways of God. Thy way, oh God, is
in the sanctuary. So what I want you to
see here, beloved, is that God is
literally inviting us. Jesus is
literally inviting us when he says,
"Seek ye first the kingdom of God." He's
saying, "I want you to seek an
understanding of the presence of God, of
the workings of God, because in in so
doing,
something's going to be added to you."
Only those who are born again
are able to seek to see the kingdom of
God and something gets added to them.
Now, we're setting the foundation,
beloved, for a message that by the grace
of God will revolutionize the way you
see your Christianity.
There is something [snorts] very
important I need you to understand here.
This holy place and most holy place was
invisible
to certain eyes.
What do you mean, pastor? Well, here's
what I mean. According to Exodus 26
and:e 36, the Bible says here,
"Thou shalt make a hanging for the door
of the tent of blue and purple and
scarlet and fine twine linen wrought
with needle work." This hanging
was the entrance into the holy place.
>> [snorts]
>> That hanging
made the tabernacle of God, the the
sanctuary of God, the kingdom of God
invisible
to the normal human eye.
Everybody put a five in the chat if you
understand what I just said. The the the
hanging
to the holy place
separated the the the gays
the the the the the Hebrew
the the the the Jewish person the
Israelite the regular normal Israelite
could not look
or seek the things within the holy and
most holy place
to enter into this veil. There were
three requirements
to enter into this veil and thus see the
kingdom of God in type.
The normal person could not do that. The
the regular
Israelite had no access to see the
kingdom of God.
Here's what had to happen
to see the kingdom of God. Notice with
me Exodus 30:18, "And y'all get ready,
get ready to have your minds blown."
Because in Exodus 30:18, the Bible says
here, "Thou shalt also make a labor of
brass, and his foot also of brass to
wash with all, and thou shalt put it
between the tabernacle of the
congregation and the altar, and thou
shalt put water therein."
Let me keep reading in verse 19 and 21.
For Aaron and his son shall wash their
hands and their feet, when they go into
the tabernacle of the congregation, they
shall wash with water that they die not.
Or when or or when they come near to the
altar to minister to burn offering made
to burn offering made by fire unto the
Lord, so shall they wash their hands and
their feet that they die not. the labor
which was the symbol of washing and and
and and and renewal and cleansing.
In order for an individual to enter into
the holy place to see the kingdom of
God, he had to first wash.
[applause]
Do y'all see this?
Do y'all Do y'all understand what we're
reading here? When Jesus says, "Except
the man be born again, he cannot see the
kingdom of God," he is referring us back
to the Old Testament sanctuary where in
order to enter beyond that hanging, that
curtain into the place of God, the
kingdom of God, the government of God
symbolized by the holy place and the
most holy place. No one could enter in
who was first not washed at the labor.
Number two, so first of all, the first
thing required was that you had to wash.
Number two,
only the priest
could wash at that labor and thus have
access
to the kingdom of God.
I need y'all to catch this. Everybody
note with me Numbers 18:7. Therefore,
thou and thy sons with thee shall keep
your priest's office for everything of
the altar, and for that within the veil
you shall serve. I have given your
priest's office unto you. I have given
your priest's office unto you as a
service of gift, and the stranger that
cometh nigh shall be put to death. No
one but the priests plural
were allowed to enter into the holy
place. In other words, only the priests
could wash at the labor and thus only
the priests had access to the kingdom of
God. again again uh um in numbers 3:10.
In fact, let me pause for a second
before I read this because the third
thing necessary
in order to see
the kingdom of God
was this.
You had to be a priest
but you could not become a priest.
Let me say it again. Number one, you had
to wash in the labor. Number two, you
had to be a priest. But number three,
you could not become a priest.
Numbers 3:10 the Bible says, "And thou
shalt appoint Aaron and his sons, and
they shall wait on their priest's
office, and the stranger that cometh
nigh shall be put to death." Notice
again with me, Exodus 29 and verse 9.
The priesthood shall be theirs for a
perpetual
statute.
All right.
So in other words, church family,
you couldn't become a priest.
You couldn't become a priest. There was
no way to become a priest. You could
only be born a priest.
You could only be born a priest. In
other words, it had to be lineage.
You couldn't just say, "Hey, I think I
want to be a priest." and see the
kingdom of God. No, no, no, no, no, no.
You had to be born a priest. And now you
can begin to understand why Jesus is
telling Nicodemus, in order to see the
kingdom of God, you've got to be born
into it. You have to be born into the
lineage.
Only the sons of Aaron could be priests.
nobody else.
You had to be born a priest in order to
see the kingdom of God.
Are y'all with me? [clears throat]
You can begin to understand now why when
Jesus says, "Except a man be born again,
he cannot see." This was a birthright
privilege.
Now, this creates a problem. This
creates a problem everyone because
here's the problem. Let me show you
something. If this is true and only the
sons of Aaron's could be priests who and
Aaron was of the tribe of Levi, then
that creates a problem for Jesus. Y'all
put a five in the chat if you understand
what I mean when I say that that creates
a problem for Jesus. Why would that
create a problem for Jesus? Two
problems. First of all, Hebrews 7:23
tells us this.
And they truly were many priests because
they were not suffered to continue by
reason of death. So in the Aaron line of
in the ar in the Aaronic lineage, all
the priests died. So there the the
priesthood was passed off to their
offspring.
But Jesus was not of the tribe of Levi.
In fact, Hebrews chapter 7 verse uh uh
uh verse 14, for it is evident that our
Lord sprang out of Judah of which tribe
Moses spake nothing concerning
priesthood. Do y'all see this? Hey, hey,
if the lineage uh must be passed on
through Aaron, then what happens
for Jesus to become our high priest? He
was not of the tribe of Levi and he
wasn't a son of Aaron.
How does this work? What does this mean?
What does this mean? Come back with me
to the book of Hebrews chapter 7 verse
or Psalms 110:4. The Bible says, "The
Lord has sworn and will not repent. Thou
art a priest forever after the order of
Melzdc." So now we're talking about
another priesthood. In other words, this
is not the priesthood of Aaron. This is
not the order of Aaron. It is the order
of Melzdc. Let's go back to the book of
Hebrews. And I'm building something
here. Please follow carefully here.
Follow carefully.
Uh the Bible says Hebrews 7:1, "If
therefore perfection were by the
Levitical priesthood, for for under it
the people received the law, what need
was there of another priest that another
priest should arise after the order of
Melzdc and not be called after the order
of Aaron?"
H
what does this mean?
Hebrews is setting the way to show us
why it is that Christ is not a priest
after the order of Aaron but after the
order of Melzdc. Please note with me,
please note with me uh uh Genesis 14:18
where we are introduced to Melzdc. The
Bible says and Melzdc,
king of Salem, brought forth bread and
wine.
Bread and wine. Y'all understand what
bread and wine symbolize in the Bible,
right? And he was the priest of the most
high God. So here's what I want you to
see, beloved. Aaron was not a king. He
was just a priest. Melzdc
was a king and a priest.
So the Bible says that Jesus would be a
priest after the order of Melzdc. Why?
because he would be both king of Salem,
meaning king of righteousness, and a
priest at the same time. Are y'all
feeling me? Are y'all understanding what
I'm saying here? I'm building something
here. I need you to understand, set the
stage of where this is going. So, let's
go back to the book of Hebrews. Hebrews
chapter 7:2.
Notice what it says. to whom also
Abraham gave a tenth part of all, first
being by interpretation king of
righteousness, after that also king of
Salem, which is, watch this, king of
peace, and then listen to this y without
father, without mother, without descent,
having neither beginning of days nor end
of life, but made like unto the son of
God, abideth a priest continually.
Okay.
So what the Bible is telling us here
beloved is that Melzdc
there is no record of his lineage. So
there's no record of who his father was
or who his mother was where he descended
from. He is human
but but there is no record of this king
priest who appears to be without father
or without mother. He's just a type. He
has a father. He has a mother, but you
cannot tell his origin, where he came
from, or where he is going.
Keep that in mind. This Melzdc seems to
be
without beginning
or ending. There's no record of his
death. There's no record of his birth.
There's no record of his lineage.
Jesus is a perfect example or a perfect
fulfillment rather of this mechazdc
order because Jesus is both king and
priest. He is without mother or father.
He is without beginning. He is divine,
without beginning and without ending.
Now what does this mean y'all? Are you
ready? I hope you're sitting down.
I hope you are sitting down
because beloved, listen to me.
In First Peter 2:9,
[clears throat]
are y'all sitting down? I hope y'all are
sitting down
because the text says, "But ye
are a chosen generation, a royal." Stop
for a second. What does royal mean?
What does royal mean? Give me, put the
word in the chat for me. When someone
says royal, what word comes to mind? If
you're royal, if you're royalty, you are
I'm waiting for it in the chat.
Royalty means kingship.
All right, let's go back to the screen.
So the text says, "But you are a chosen
generation, a royal priesthood." What
kind of priesthood is this, y'all? It's
a priesthood that is combining king and
priest. In other words, beloved, in
Christ,
we
H
in Christ we become a part of the Melzdc
order
of priests.
We become part of a kingly priesthood, a
holy nation, a pecular people. Now I
need you to understand beloved how does
one how does one end up being a priest
in this order.
It is not by becoming one.
Y'all put a y'all put a 10 in the chat
if this is suddenly coming together. Now
remember to see the kingdom of God there
are three requirements. Number one, you
must wash at the labor. Number two, you
must be a priest. And number three, you
must be born a priest. You can't become
a priest.
It is impossible for the world to become
a part of the ironic priesthood. Why?
Because most of the world are not
offspring of Aaron or of the tribe of
Levi. So what Jesus does, beloved, Jesus
comes as a fulfillment of the Melzdc
priesthood to open the way
to open the way for anyone who accepts
Christ to become a part of his lineage.
And when you become a part of Christ's
lineage, you are born again. You are
washed by the labor. You become a priest
and thus are part of the priesthood who
now has access to the kingdom of God.
Are y'all feeling me?
Are y'all understanding? Listen. In the
Old Testament, the Bible says uh of
Israel, they were to be unto me a
kingdom of priests and a holy nation. So
So I need you to understand the
difference here. [cough]
A kingdom of priests simply referred to
a a nation of priests.
But this is not the Melzdc order. Why?
Because priests were not kings.
However, however, in the Melzdc order,
priests are kings just like the original
Jesus Christ himself,
who is both king and priest. And so
again, this is why Jesus said in Matthew
3:7, "Marvel not, I said unto thee, you
must be born again." Now watch this,
y'all. Are y'all ready for some fire?
Are y'all ready for some fire? Listen to
this. The wind bloweth where it listeth,
and that you hear the sound thereof, but
you cannot tell, listen to me, its
origin,
or where it ends up.
Sounds like Melzdc.
No origin. You Where did he come from?
Where's he going? What Jesus is saying,
beloved, is that those who are born
again of the Melzdc order no longer have
earthly mother or father. They have
they have been born again from above
like the wind, like the spirit. And yes,
while you still have an earthly father
and an earthly mother, those who are
born again are not born again of flesh.
There is no human descent. There is no
human. Someone didn't cause you to be
born again. You were born again of the
spirit. And thus, like the spirit who
you cannot tell from whence it came or
whether it goeth. There is no beginning
and no ending. In that very same way,
those who are of the Melzdc order will
live forever and ever,
and they have no human origin.
[snorts]
This is why the Bible says, This is why
the Bible says in Revelation 1:6, he has
made us kings and priests. That's the
Melzdc order, y'all. He has made us
kings and priests unto God and his
father. To him be glory and dominion
forever and ever. Amen. And Revelation
5:10 tells us, "And he has made unto us,
he has made us unto our God kings and
priests, [clears throat] and we shall
reign on the earth." I need y'all to
understand and catch this, beloved. This
is absolutely powerful. In Isaiah 61:6,
it says, "But you shall be named priests
of the Lord. Men shall call you the
ministers of our God. You shall eat of
the riches of the Gentiles and in their
glory you shall boast. In other words,
what I want you to understand, beloved,
is that this is the lineage that you are
born into. You cannot just take it on
your own. And now listen beloved, listen
to me. Now these verses will begin to
make sense. When the Bible says in Titus
3:5, "Not by works of righteousness
which we have done, but according to his
mercy he saved us by the washing of
regeneration and the renewing of the
Holy Ghost. He washes us at the labor."
And thus says, "You are a priest." Why?
Listen, only priests are born again. If
you are born again, you are a priest
after the order of Melzdc. Why? Because
only priests can enter into the kingdom
of God. Only priests had the privilege
of going beyond the veil and seeing the
inner workings of God, seeing the
kingdom of God, seeing how God operates,
seeing the presence and glory of God.
And so Jesus says in John 15:3, "Now you
are clean through the word which I have
spoken unto you." What he's saying is I
have made you priests. You have been
born again so that as priests you can
see and seek the kingdom of God. So
here's the question now. Now now we need
to now we need to understand okay okay
if I'm a priest then what is the work of
the priest?
What is a priest supposed to be doing?
Priests were to offer up sacrifices.
Priests were to maintain the perpetual
fire that was burning on the altar.
Priests were to distinguish between the
holy and the unholy, the clean and the
unclean. Priests were to teach the
Israelites of God's laws and his
statutes. Priests were to pronounce
blessings over the people. Priests were
to serve as judges in difficult cases.
Priests were to teach the law of God.
priests were to preserve knowledge in
their lips. This is the work of the
priest. And so now we can begin to
understand why verses like this are in
the Bible. In 1 Peter chapter 2:5,
in 1 Peter chapter 2:5, the Bible says
this. The Bible says, "You also as
lively stones are built up a spiritual
house, a holy priesthood to offer up
spiritual sacrifices acceptable to God
by Jesus Christ, the priest." Beloved,
as a priest, we are to be offering up
spiritual sacrifices. As priests, the
Bible says, "I beseech you therefore,
brethren, by the mercies of God, that
you present your bodies a living
sacrifice, holy, acceptable to God,
which is your reasonable service." As
priests, we ought to be offering up our
bodies as a living sacrifice. As
priests, the Bible says, "I will praise
the name of God with a song. I will
magnify him with thanksgiving. This also
shall please the Lord better than an ox
or bulock that has horns and hoofs.
Priests are to give up offerings of
praise and thanksgiving." Psalms 116:17,
I will offer to you thanksgiving.
I will call upon the name of the Lord.
But here is something I especially want
to focus on, beloved, because what I
need you to understand, beloved, is that
there is such a thing as the priest's
heart. The Bible says in Psalm 51:17,
"The sacrifices of God are a broken
spirit, a broken and a contrite heart.
These, oh God, you will not despise."
Listen,
check this out, y'all.
The evidence,
the evidence
that you are, that you see the kingdom
of God and that you have entered into
the kingdom of God is that you are a
priest.
And the evidence that you are a priest
is that you are offering up the
sacrifice of a broken spirit and a
contrite heart. A humble heart, a
converted heart.
Wow.
Oh.
So to be born again means to have a
converted heart means to actually be a
priest.
And only the priests could enter into
the kingdom of God.
Pastor, you telling me only priests will
be saved? Yes.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Only priests enter the
kingdom of God. Beloved,
only priests enter the kingdom of God.
But the the the evidence that you are a
priest
is that you have a broken heart and a
contrite spirit. You have a new heart.
In fact, in fact, check out our great
high priest. The Bible says, "Now we
have not a high priest which cannot be
touched with the feelings of our
infirmity, but was in all points tempted
like as we are, yet without sin. Let us
therefore come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and help
in the time of need." What I want y'all
to catch here, beloved, is that our high
priest was touched with the feeling of
our infirmities. He sympathized
with us. He was touched with our
feelings. In other words, beloved, one
of the greatest evidences that you are a
priest is that you have a heart like
Jesus that that that has compassion
on the weak. Compassion with the
struggling compassion. In fact, let me
show it to you in the book of Isaiah
53:4. Verse three and four. He is
despised and rejected of men. A man of
sorrows and acquainted with grief, our
grief, and we hid as it were our faces
from him. He was despised and we
esteemed him not. Surely he has borne
our griefs and carried our sorrows. And
yet we did esteem him stricken, smitten
of God, and afflicted. In other words,
beloved,
the sign of a priest is that he has
compassion on the people he has been
called to intercede for.
The sign of a priest
is that he's offering up sacrifices
and praise. His contrite and broken
heart leads him to have compassion
on others.
It's what I'm going to call the priest's
hearts.
That is the single most
important sign that you have been born
again when you have a heart of
compassion like our great high priest
Jesus Christ.
Do y'all understand what I'm saying?
You cannot take this priesthood. You
can't. So, so
y'all remember a guy by the name of
Kora?
Put a one in the chat. If you remember a
guy by the name of Kora from the Old
Testament, put a one in the chat if you
remember a guy by the name of Kora in
the Old Testament. And if you remember
that name, if you heard, if you hear
that name, you're like, I know who Kora
is. You'll remember that Kora was a
Levite, but he wasn't of the sons of
Aaron.
And Kora wanted the priesthood,
which was only available through
lineage, through bloodline.
Numbers 16 1-3. Now Kora the son of Isar
the son of Kohath the son of Levi with
Dayan and Abyram the sons of Eliab and
on the son of Pelth sons of Ruben took
men and they rose up before Moses with
some of the children of Israel 250
leaders of the congregation
representatives of the community men of
renown. They gathered together against
Moses and Aaron and said unto them, you
take too much upon yourselves for all
the congregation is holy. Every one of
them and the Lord is among them. Why
then do you exalt yourselves above the
assembly of the Lord? The argument was,
hey, whoever wants to be a priest can be
a priest.
It's not just through lineage.
Whoever wants to be a priest can be a
priest. Now, beloved, I need you to
understand that in a sense, yes, but in
a sense, no.
Because beloved, through Jesus, he has
opened up the priesthood to anybody that
wants to be a part of it. However, you
still must be of the lineage of Jesus.
Watch what happens, right? So, so Kora
wants the priesthood. And the Bible says
in verse 5, "And he spake unto Cor that
is Moses, and to all his company,
saying, even tomorrow the Lord will show
who are his, and who is holy, and will
cause him to come near unto him, even
unto him who has chosen whom he has
chosen will cause to come near unto him.
This do take your sensors, Kora, and all
his company,
and put fire therein, and put incense in
them before the Lord on the moral. And
it shall be that the man whom the Lord
chooses, he shall be holy. You take too
much upon you, ye sons of Levi.
This is very interesting, you guys. Kora
wants the priesthood, but Kora does not
have the bloodline of the priesthood.
Kora is not of the sons of Aaron. is not
in the lineage of Aaron, but he wants
the priesthood.
He wants the priesthood
evidently because he wants to see the
kingdom of God. He wants to be able to
get in there and see the the the
candlestick and the and the se and the
and the h table of showbread and the
altar of incense and the ark of the
covenant. He wants to see the kingdom of
God. But there's a problem. There's a
problem. You see,
Kora's name means ice.
H
Kora's name means
ice.
Remember what I said earlier?
The priest is to have a care for the
people. The priest is to have a heart
for the people.
the priest. In fact, according to
Leviticus 16:12, the fire upon the altar
shall be burning in it. It shall not be
put out, and the priest shall burn wood
on it every morning, and lay the burnt
offering and order upon it, and he shall
burn thereon the fat of the peace
offerings. Every morning the fire shall
be burning on the altar. It shall never
go out. The priest's role responsibility
was to make sure the fire kept going.
Why is this significant beloved? Because
in the Song of Solomon 8 verse 6, the
Bible says here, Song of Solomon 8:6,
set me as a seal upon thine heart and as
a seal upon thine arm. For love is as
strong as death. Jealousy is as cruel as
a grave. The coals thereof are coals of
fire which has a most behemic flame.
Many waters cannot quench love. Fire
that the priests were to be were to keep
burning was a symbol of love. But Kora's
name means ice. Beloved,
you cannot be a priest if the love of
God is not burning in your heart.
Period. You cannot be a priest if the
love of God for people is not burning in
your hearts. If you are if you have an a
heart of ice,
if you have a heart of ice that does not
care for other people, please
understand, no pun intended. And then
maybe, pun intended,
if you're operating
with a heart of ice,
if you're operating with a heart that
does not care for other people, if
you're operating with a heart
that doesn't have the love of God
burning in it, you cannot be a part of
the priesthood. This is why you must be
born of water and the spirit, meaning
water and fire. This is why Jesus said
that he was This is why John said that
Jesus would baptize with water and with
fire, with the spirit and with fire.
Here,
remember how earlier we talked about we
talked about how how if you seek first
the kingdom of God, then all these
things shall be added onto you. Remember
what the things were that Jesus was
talking about? He was talking about
clothing and food. And then he says,
"Listen, don't care about those things
like the Gentiles do. They naturally
just care about those things. I have
greater clothing
and greater food."
And now I need y'all to understand
something. Now I need y'all to
understand something. You see,
when the priests were inaugurated,
they were given
food and clothing.
Yeah. I'm going just wait and let y'all
just rest. I'm going to let y'all just
sit on that, y'all. I'm gonna let y'all
just sit on that for a minute.
If you were a priest,
you were automatically granted
certain food that nobody else could eat
could have access to and certain
clothing that no one else could have
access to. Seek ye first the kingdom of
God and all these things and his
righteousness and all these things shall
be
added
unto you.
In Leviticus 25:28 verse5, then you
shall take the garments, put the tunic
on Aaric, on Aaron, and the robe and the
ephod and the ephod and the breastplate
and gird him with the intricately woven
band of the ephod. You shall put the
turban on his head and put the holy
crown on turban. Listen, [clears throat]
God will clothe you if you seek first
the kingdom of God.
Y'all
y'all thought he was talking about God
will will grant you a suit and a tie
and the clothing when you need it.
Beloved, listen to me. There are people
living in poverty who don't have the
clothing who who God has clothed
because they are kings and priests. Do
you understand what I'm saying?
Seek ye first the kingdom of God. How?
Well, in order to seek it, you got to be
a priest. In order to seek it, you have
to be washed at the labor. In order
[snorts] to seek it, you can't become a
priest. You have to have been born a
priest. How can a man enter into the
womb? Sec. You have to be born a priest.
But when you are born a priest, when you
are born a priest, when you become when
you enter the kingdom of God, when you
see the kingdom of God, I will clothe
you with the garments of the priest.
Not only were the priests granted
clothing, but there were there was food
that only the priests could eat. Take no
heed for what you will eat and what you
will put on because God our father in
heaven will clothe you with such with
such things. By the way, one of the
things that Aaron was to have on his
person that the priests were aware
notice with me in Exodus 28:9. And Aaron
shall bear the names of the children of
Israel in the breastplate of judgment
upon his heart when he goeth into the
holy place for memorial before the Lord
continually. Beloved, to be a priest,
you must bear the names of God's people
on your heart. To be a priest, you must
have a love in your heart
for those whom God loves.
And so the Bible says in in Malachi
chapter [clears throat] 2, [cough]
Malachi chapter 2 and verse 7, the Bible
says here, "For the priest's lips should
have kept knowledge. They should seek
the law at his mouth. For he is the
messenger of the Lord's host, but your
departed out of the way. You have caused
many to stumble at the law. You have
corrupted the covenant of Levi, sayith
the Lord of hosts. Therefore, have I
made you contemptable and base before
all the people, according as you have
not kept my ways, and have been partial
in my law. What I need you to
understand, beloved, is that a priest
must abide by the law of God. And what
is the law of God? Romans 13:8 tells us,
"Oh, no man anything but to love one
another. For he that loveth another hath
fulfilled the law. For this, thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
kill. Thou shalt not steal. Thou shalt
not bear false witness. Thou shalt not
covet. And if there be any other
commandment, it is briefly comprehended
in this saying, namely, thou shalt love
thy neighbor as thyself. Please
understand, beloved, that when, listen
to me, you can be Seventh Day Adventist
all day long. And if you don't have love
in your heart,
you are not a priest. You have not
entered the kingdom of God. You have not
seen the kingdom of God. Because a true
priest
has been washed at the labor and has the
heart of the priest
has been born again and has a heart like
the great high priest Jesus Christ
himself.
This is why, beloved, in the book of
Isaiah chapter 58, when we are told in
Isaiah 58, when the Bible says, "Is not
this the fast I have chosen to loose the
bands of wickedness, and to undo the
heavy burdens, and to let the oppressed
go free, and that you break every yoke?
Is it not to deal thy bread to the
hungry, and that thou bring the poor
that are cast out to thy house? When you
see the naked that you cover him, and
you hide not yourself from your own
flesh, then shall thy light break forth
as a morning, and thine health shall
spring forth speedily, and thy
righteousness shall go before thee, and
the glory of the Lord shall be thy
reward. All I want you to understand,
beloved, all I want you to understand
and see is this,
that a true priest
who has been born again will have the
heart of the priest. And that is the
heart that has the law of God written on
it.
Let me show you. We're getting ready to
close. We got two more things and then
we're going to wrap this up. Okay, two
more portions of scripture. Matthew 5
and then we're going to go to Luke
chapter 10. Matthew 5. And I want you to
note with me. Matthew chapter 5. Matthew
chapter 5. But I say unto you, in fact,
I got to go back. Isaiah 53:12.
Therefore will I divide him a portion
with the great, and he shall divide the
spoil with the strong, because he has
poured out his soul unto death. He was
numbered with the transgressors and he
bear the sins of many and made
intercession for the transgressors.
That's what I want y'all to lock in on.
Jesus did not just make intercession for
the holy. In fact, he came not to call
the righteous to repentance, but
sinners. In Matthew 5:44, the Bible says
this, "But I say unto you, love your
enemies,
bless them that curse you, and do good
to them that hate you, and pray for them
which despitefully use and persecute
you, that you may be the children of
your father which is in heaven. For he
maketh the son to rise on the evil and
on the good, and sendeth rain on the
just and on the unjust." Watch this. For
if you love only them which love you,
what is your reward?
Do not even the publicans the same? And
if you salute your brethren only, what
do you more than others? Do not even the
publicans so be ye therefore perfect,
even as your father which is in heaven
is perfect. I want y'all to understand,
beloved, that when God talks about
perfection,
when God talks about perfection,
he's talking about it within a context
of the priest's heart.
Perfection
is not loving those who love you back.
Perfection. [snorts]
God's definition of perfection right
here. Perfection
is loving those
who don't love you back.
And I'm going to be doing a whole a
whole another sermon on this.
But I think to a large degree, a lot of
us fail to understand the perfection
that will be required of God's people at
the end of time and why it will be
required of God's people at the end of
time. Because if perfection
is loving those who persecute you and
there is coming a time when the
persecution will be unlike anything any
other generation has faced.
Then there is a reason why
the final generation
is going to be tested the way that they
are.
And most people don't understand,
[clears throat]
they're on a totally different
definition of perfection.
All right, I'mma leave that right there.
We're going to come back to that, but I
need to close with this, y'all. I need
to close with this. In Luke 10:2,
the Bible says, "And behold, a certain
lawyer stood up and tempted him, saying,
Master, what shall I do to inherit
eternal life?" And he said unto him,
"What is written in the law? How readest
thou?"
[clears throat and cough]
And he answered and said, "Thou shalt
love the Lord thy God with all thy
heart, with all thy soul, with all thy
strength, and with all thy mind, and thy
neighbor as thyself."
And he said unto him, "Thou has
answered," Right. This do, and thou
shalt live. But he willing to justify
himself said unto Jesus, "And who is my
neighbor?" And Jesus answered and said,
"Now watch what Jesus uses here." Okay?
Watch what Jesus does here. A certain
man went down from Jerusalem to Jericho
and fell among thieves, which stripped
him of his reignment and wounded him and
departed, leaving him half dead. Now
watch this. And by chance [cough]
there came down a certain priest
that way. And when he saw him, he passed
by on the other side. And likewise a
Levite
when he was at the place came and looked
on him and passed by on the other side.
Why is Jesus using the priest and the
Levite?
Are y'all following? Are y'all
understanding what I'm asking right
here? Why is Jesus using the priest and
the Levite?
Because what you're about to read in the
rest of this parable of how this man,
[clears throat]
this this Samaritan
literally functions
in the role of the priest.
while not being the lineage of the
priesthood.
And you can imagine in the mind of the
Jews, oh the Samaritan, no, no, no, no,
no, no. We can't. You say the Samaritan.
No, no, no, no. He's No, definitely not.
But here here is a Samaritan, someone
outside the lineage of Levi
doing the work that they were supposed
to do. So when Jesus comes along and
they treated Jesus as a Samaritan, when
Jesus comes along, thou art a Samaritan,
you have a devil. when Jesus comes along
and initiates this priesthood of Melzdc
saying listen I am not of your of the
lineage of of of Levi
but I'm the king priest who is doing the
work that you all failed to do and now
anyone
who says I want to do that work too I
want to be a part of that priesthood the
the order of Melzdc I want to see the
kingdom of God, I want the heart of the
priest. Jesus says,
if you seek that,
if you seek that, then all these things,
the food,
the bread of righteousness,
the robe of righteousness,
the stuff that only the priest could
wear and eat will become yours.
Beloved, it is as if what Jesus was
trying to show us in the Old Testament
was that the priest was the arch type,
the prototype of the man and woman that
God ultimately wants us to be in Christ.
Wow.
We hear you're your royal priesthood. We
don't even understand what Jesus is
saying. You're the order of Melazdc.
When you're born again, you have no
beginning.
You're born just like the spirit. You're
born of the spirit. You're like the
wind.
You will have no ending like that great
high priest Jesus.
You have no no earthly lineage.
mother, no mother, no father. Why?
Because you've been born again of the
spirit.
But the greatest evidence
that this transaction has happened
is that you have the priest's heart.
>> [snorts]
>> Many a professed people of God will be
lost
debating doctrine, debating
righteousness by faith, debating
perfection, debating the the debating
all these things, knowing the truth, but
not knowing the truth,
never seeing the kingdom of God,
never seeking the kingdom kingdom of
God.
May the Lord help us to have that
contrite heart, that contrite spirit,
that broken heart. That is the evidence
that the seal of God is on upon our is
upon our hearts. As Song of Solomon
says, "Set me as a seal upon your heart
because the fire of God's love is
burning within me." If you want that
fire,
if you want to seek, you understand what
it means. Oh, to seek the kingdom of God
means I've got to be born again.
Which means I have to be a priest.
Which means the only way I can be a
priest is to be born again.
Is to be washed by the spirit of God, by
the word of God. Lord, help me to be a
priest to see the kingdom of God. And
let me tell you, beloved,
[cough and clears throat]
in entering into the sanctuary like
David, we will be able to say, "Now I
understand.
Now I understand. Now I understand why.
I understand why I lost my son. I
understand why. I understand the wise. I
understand that God is going to make
this right. I understand that even
though things look messed up now, I
understand that even though I can't
explain this here, I understand that
justice is coming. I understand that
mercy is coming. I understand why.
Because those who enter into the temple
of God, those who seek the kingdom of
God, all these things will be added to
them.
They will see, they will understand,
they will gain, they will they will
receive the righteousness of Christ.
They will receive the food that that is
designed to sustain the priest. They
will by the grace of God have all these
things added to them. If it is your
desire to have all these things added to
you, you don't go out and get it
yourself. They are added to you once you
are born again.
H
Lord, grant me this.
Teach me to seek the kingdom of God. If
that's your desire, put that five in the
chat. Put that five in the chat. Lord,
it is my desire. Teach me for 2026 and
and forward to live as a priest.
Heavenly Father,
I thank you for speaking to us. I thank
you Lord for opening up the word to us
to help us to understand when you said
seek ye first the kingdom of God and all
these things should be added onto you
what you actually meant by that
because strangers cannot seek the
kingdom of God only the priest could
Lord thank you for showing us that you
have called us to be priests
to follow the great high priest after
the order of Melzdc
Thank you, Lord.
Grant us the priest's heart.
Grant us the priest's clothing.
Grant us the priest's food.
And Lord, may we reflect the light and
the power of our great high priest Jesus
Christ
is our prayer in Jesus name. May we
love, may we intercede, may we plead and
be the priests you've called us to be.
In Jesus name we pray. Amen. And amen.
We're going to put the link um to the
altar live
um I'm sorry, the uh mighty network's
afterglow. And I want to thank you all
for joining us today. I pray that this
message um has been a blessing uh to
you. I pray that um that you will walk
differently
uh from this day forward. And again, may
God bless you uh for those of you that
that would like to join us on the um the
mighty networks uh afterlow where we
discuss the Sabbath school as well as
the divine as well as the sermon from
the divine service. I will see you then.
And uh again, may God bless you and keep
you and draw you ever closer to him.
Amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at living
manana.urch. We are not just here for
Sabbath service. We have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our [music] programming will
continue to bless you. Please continue
to pray for us as we fulfill God's
mission to go into all the world with
the gospel of Jesus Christ.